Game 00

Game Day

Game Date: 07/12/15

Date in Play: (4) Tarsakh 20, 1491

TLDR

Heroes came to Red Larch
Went to the local tavern to have a meal.

Asked watress about town, she told them about the 6 men in masks

They had a brief encounter with a halfling that was scared out of the tavern.
After settling into their rooms a storm came.

Detailed Entry

The heroes arrive in Red Larch their first thought was to stroll the streets. In the town of Red Larch there are tailors, tanners, leather workers, bakers, and of course an inn and a separate tavern.

Wyer made his way to the bath house to clean up and they said it will be ready in an hour. The others made their way to the bakery. After trying out the Sword Coast Famous Crumble Cake, they got some Cheese Toast and mad their way through the rest of the town.

They finally settled on Helm at Highsun Tavern. The waitress was kind and served them food and the local ale. It was a great meal the filled up their bellies. While in the tavern they talked to the waitress who talked about town gossip. She said Everyone has a story. Barikhol asked her about what her story around town is. She told them a story about how she saw six men wearing metal mask strolling through town.

"I was taking out the trash when I saw 6 men heading up the side road to the Long Road. They were wearing these masks made of metal. I didn't want anything to do with it and it kind of creeped me out so I ran back inside."

While she was telling this story this Halfling was rolling his eyes and making a 'humf' sound as she was telling her tale. All a sudden he heard in his head "What do you know of it" (forgive me I am an audio memorizer. This part was typed and I cannot recall what was said). The Halfling jumped up and started yelling out. "Who said that?" "What do you want?"

Josephus asked him "What are you going on about little man?"

"Didn't you hear that?" the Halfling asks. "That loud voice."

"I didn't hear anything did you?" Josephus asks the group.

The lights started flickering in the tavern. The Halfling was scared that some kind of demon was attacking him, well he was only half right. Wyer noticed that Armond was whispering under his breath. They caught each other's notice but didn’t say anything.

The Halfling said "I better go." and he ran out the building.

After the meal Wyer went to his scheduled bath (inspiration). Armond went to secure a room with lock boxes.

The heroes meet up in their room to discuss what they wanted to do next. This is when the storm came. The storm was the power of a tropical storm. Armond staring out the window studied the pattern and noticed this may be caused by some kind of magical backlash.

What is causing these storms? Who are these men in the metal masks? What else do these people in this town know? Find out next time.

Prev | Home | Game Notes | Game 01

Game 02

Game Day

Game Date: 08/24/15

Date in Play: (4) Tarsakh 21, 1491, (4) Tarsakh 22, 1491

TLDR

After taking a break the heroes headed to the cave where there was supposed to be treasure.

The only thing they found was Stirges

Going back to Red Larch the heroes had lunch and then decided to go to Lance Rock in the morning.
On their travels they ran into magical fog.
Lance Rock turned out to be a Zombie Cave.
The heroes got jumped and took a few good lumps. They decided to heal up back at the entrance and try again after a long rest.

Detailed Entry

The adventure begun sitting in a field staring at a skull. The heroes decided to take a short rest after the hallucination effect hit Josephus . After the all healed up they packed their things to go to the treasure cave.

This was a couple hour walk, but they quickly found the right location. Josephus found all the right markings the lady from Red Larch told him. The cave was easy to see and the entrance was a bit thin. Most of the party had to turn sideways to get through.

Once inside they were attacked by Stirges. These things started jumping out of the rocks and walls to latch themselves onto the adventurers. Only a couple bits, but they there were able to fight off these blood sucking beast.

The heroes started looking around the cave, but they found no treasure. After a bit of thinking they concluded that the boot prints that were on the outside of this cave must have been others who found the treasure first.

A little heartbroken and a bit jealous they set off back towards town. About an hour into their travels they felt the ground rumble and shake. Out of the ground jump an Ankhegs . The Ankheg is a huge insect looking monster with many slender limbs and large antenna. It burrows underground and hunts from bellow. The one that jumped out of the ground at the players was scary. They knew if they engaged it they would most certainly die. There were others, they knew this because they could feel the grounds still shaking.

Knowing they didn't have a chance they started to run. Acid was spraying around them and they were sliding, rolling, jumping, and praying. They ran and ran. Eventually the monster decided they were not worth it and the heroes learned that sometimes running is a better option than fighting. The North is a dangerous place, and today the heroes learned this first hand.

After returning to Red Larch the heroes treated themselves to a hearty meal and Wyer took a much needed bath. Haeleeya was closing up shop, but said she would be able to take one more customer for the night. Wyer paid 2 silver to show his appreciation and she started preparing the bath right away.

Wyer started friendly conversation with her that very quickly turned into flirting. Haeleeya told him about how her and her sister came to this town. Her parents died and her sister and Haeleeya ran off into the woods. After a while they got lost, but was found by a ranger from the emerald enclave. He found them, gave them food, and took them to red larch . Here they grew up and started a business. Wyer did discover that she is single and kept the conversation going throughout the bath. That night Wyer returned to the room satisfied with the evening.

The next morning the heroes decided to go and adventure to Lance Rock to find out what evils live within. They have been told that it is full of Fell Magic and they have also been told there is a plague. Now it is time to find out what really ails this place.

Once they woke up, ate, and got prepared they started heading south. On the road they were greeted by a dense fog that would hinder their vision to only 10 feet. Calling out in the fog did not get them any replies. Eventually the fog just dispersed and was completely gone. Looking to the skies it was a bright sunny day so this fog seems to be as unnatural as the rest of these random storms.

Once they arrived at Lance Rock they noticed the rock was not natural to this location. Looking at the ground and stones that surrounded this rock, it looks, almost, like it was placed here. They also saw a sign that read:

"Come no closer
lest you catch
the disfiguring plague
that afflicts me!

The Lord of Lance Rock "

They saw this sign 2 more times before they arrived at the cave's entrance. As soon as they went inside they saw a body on the ground. Wyer ran up to the body and it stood up to attack him. It was a zombie. The heroes battled it and killed it. They now know this cave is plagued with monsters, and they must defeat the evil inside.

Barikhol took the lead since he can see without a light source. The first room he entered he was attacked from overhead by Zombies throwing rocks. The zombies jumped down to try and eat Barikhol , but he was quick and his teammates were not far behind. The quickly dispatched the zombies. Looking around the room they saw a bloody rock where others have died. They took a left (heading south) and the path was tight enough that one person could fit through at a time. The wall had natural sharp ridges that point towards them as they walked through.

Peeking into the room there were 3 zombies dressed as a bear, a girl, and a jester. The Bear and the girl seemed to be acting like they are chasing one another while the jester mimed laughter. They were ordered to act unless they were approached by an intruder, then lead them into false safety and attack.

The heroes decided to take a look at the other room first. So they creeped back and found a room where all the zombies were chained to the wall by a hook. They were all dormant until an adventurer enters the room, then they started reaching out and snarling. The zombies were missing their hands and their hands were replaced with weapons.

The heroes started taking them out one by one till three of them pulled themselves off the walls and started attacking. Once the heroes eliminated the threat and finished the remainder of the zombies on the walls, they moved back to the room with the dressed up zombies.

The zombies did as they were told, pretended to ignore the heroes and the moment they were within range they took their readied attacks. After this room they heard a voice from the next room. "What was that? Someone is here? Who would enter my cave? Ok everyone get ready, places, places! We will show these intruders not to mess with the Lord of Lance Rock ."

The heroes felt pretty beat from this and decided to go back to the entrance so they could rest and get back their strength. They setup a light to make it through the next 8 hours and rest.

Will the Heroes plan work? Will they find the cause of this? Who is this Lord of Lance Rock ?

Game 01 | Home | Game Notes | Game 03

Game 08

Game Day

Game Date: 04/04/16

Date In Play:: (5) Mirtul 04, 1491 ; (5) Mirtul 05, 1491 ;

TLDR

The heroes arrived at a town called Ospit
Ospit healers are out of work because of the Law of 5e. The only thing they have left is selling healing potions. They sell them for cheap.
The heroes continued the next day to Beliard
Tyelknowle went to the local church and met with Victoria , a lady of sune.
Victoria told Ty about the Delegation and how they were on their way to Summit Hall.
The others went to speak to the town. They were directed to a man named Eann.
Eann told the heroes about the Birds along the Dessarian Road.
They went to investigate and found one still alive.
They were attacked by soldiers on giant vultures.
They captured an Air Genasi soldier and they brought back the only survivor.

Detailed Entry

(Sorry, I am really off my game and have been super busy. These notes are probably going to be shorted versions as well)

The story started as the adventurers were coming into a town called Ospit. The town was a little dilapidated and didn’t seem to have many visitors for it being on such a main road. They approached a man wearing a coat. The coat could have once been a perfectly clean white coat, but it is showing it's years. He welcomes the heroes to the town "Welcome travelers, how may our towns people assist you?"

The heroes pointed out that the town seems to have no visitors. The man replied, "Ahhh yes. We were once a thriving town. This was more of a research and aid center, but our services are not needed anymore. For years scholars have traveled here to study medicine, surgery, and all sorts of mundane and magical healing. But ever sense the law of 5 came about, we are no longer needed in the world."

When asked about the law of 5 he replied, "The law of 5…"

Another interrupts from the distance, "Don't forget about subsection e."

"Right," he continues "The law of 5e undid all of our hard work and now adventurers can do in a nights rest what they use to adventure here because they were in need of services."

The heroes suggested that they adapt to the new law, "Oh we have. Some of our people who have been working in the field for years are now mere potion brewers. We are having a sale on our potions, 20gp a bottle."

He heroes bought up some supplies and took rest in the town for the night. (Erin, your character may have made some potion purchases at this time. Just let me know at the start of next game.)

The next day the heroes arrived in Beliard . They started asking the local towns people about the delegation and they had some wild theories. Ty went to speak with the local church. It was a lady of sune by the name of Victoria she told him what she knew about the delegation, how they headed south to stop by Summit Hall because one their knights died and he was from that town. He had major burns from some kind of creature.

Josephus , Armond , Rowena and Barikhol went to the local tavern to speak with others. Armond started asking questions to the bar maid and she told him what she had heard. They went toward Summit Hall but never made it there. She knows this because a traveler from Summit Hall said they never made it and he didn't pass them on the road either. The heros quickly noticed that the town has a twag dialect that can sometimes be hard to understand. Barikhol had no problem falling right back into this accent.

Since Ty wasn't there Barikhol wanted to bring up how he has been feeling about Ty.

Another patron of the tavern told the heroes to speak with Eann (Sorry if I gave another name, whatever I gave I can go with that, but this was the name I had written) about what he saw out on the Dessarin Road.

The heroes take his advice and head down to Eann 's Apple Grove, passing Rowena on the way. When they arrived at Eann farm he asks "er ye flla lost?" The heroes informed him that they are looking for Eann .

"Oy, dat be may. Wut can I dou fur ya?" he asked

Barikhol jumped in, "we be needen sum help, ther be a delegation travlin down the Dessarin Road n dey seemed ta disappear. I hear ye be knowin sumt'in aboot dis."

Eann replies "ay, I has, it be nice to hear trav'las who talkin proper. Der ha been attalks on the Dessarin Road I sau wid me own eyes. A large bird swooped out of de sky n pulcked a travla off the rud." Eann buddy claimed he was a drunkin fool, but Eann refuted this and said it was true.

The heroes asked a few more clarifying questions about the bird and where it happened, and if they knew to whom. The farmer was able to answer where, but didn't know much about the bird and who it was. No one claimed the missing person.

He heroes meet up, trade information, and head down the road. On the way they see vultures flying about a mile off the trail. They decided to go investigate. Once they get over there they find the wreckage of what could have been the delegation. Going through the dead bodies they saw soldiers with the black coats and red axes. Barikhol knew it was the guards of mirabar.

There was one still alive. He was badly injured. They pulled him from the wreckage and bandaged him up. This is when they heard the screech of a giant vulture. Three beast came flying out of the skys and down towards the heroes. A fight broke out. Armond started his eldritch blast, Barikhol pulled out his throwing axes, Josephus pulled out his bow, Rowena summoned her sorcery, and Ty pulled out his bow.

There were many trades during the battle, but two of the highlights where when Ty ripped the cape off the soldier and threw it over the bird and prepared to give a lift to Barikhol to land on it.

Also when Barikhol got swept up into a grapple from the air elemental and it turned out doing this was a big mistake.

After the fight the heroes took the air elemental and the survivor back to town.

Game 07 | Home | Game Notes | Game 09

Game 10.5

Game Day

Game Date: 10/03/16

In Play Date:: (5) Mirtul 08, 1491; (5) Mirtul 09, 1491;

TLDR

The heroes regrouped to discuss their options.
They decided fighting the Feathergale Knights was a bad idea, they better play along and see what they can get from Lord Commander Thurl Merosska.
Thurl gave the heroes information where The Cult of the Black Earth are hiding. It is a place called the Sacred Stone Monastery .
Thurl is hiding something.
The heroes traveled to the Monastery and setup watch.

Detailed Entry

The heroes came together in one of their rooms. Armond was inspecting the ring as Josephus and Barikhol was retelling the story of fighting the manticore.

After, Rowena and Tyelknowle caught up the team in what they found.

The general consensus of the party is they do not trust the Feathergale Knights . They feel the place is infiltrated by one of the elemental cults . The problem is, they are quite out numbered. Picking a fight with the Feathergale Knights and if they are bad, there are way more of them than the heroes. Their best bet is to go about their adventure and see if they can get anything from the Lord Commander Thurl Merosska.

The party agreed to this and got some sleep for the night.

The next morning the heroes woke up to the break of dawn and the smell of wonderful food. Coming out of their rooms they saw the Feathergale Knights working to prepare for breakfast.

One of the higher ranking knights was assigning duties. She looks over to the guest and asks "You joining us for breakfast?"

When the heroes nodded or spoke that they were, she tells them "Great, everyone in the spire has a job, even the guest." Then she assigns them some tasks to do. Josephus got to go work in the kitchen. Rowena got to go work with the hippogriffs. The rest of the heroes got assigned random duties.

Once food was prepared and out everyone came together and ate. The heroes noticed that most of the knights at the table, we unarmed. They were not even being cautious of their visitors anymore. The knights welcomed and initiated conversation. People told stories of their homes, politics, loved ones, and more.

After the meal, everyone went back to their duties. The Lord Commander asked the heroes to join him in his chambers.

Ty and Rowena noticed the letter was no longer visible when entering. The Lord Commanders chambers was pristine. Everything had a place and everything was perfectly clean. This is a soldier that takes great care of his living quarters and this may give some insight to his expectations of his fellow knight's quarters.

Merosska motions everyone to take a seat, there seems to be enough places for everyone. "It looks like you all are ready to get back out there. I want you to know there is always a welcomed room for you here at the spire." He entertains questions from the heroes.

[If there are any questions you may have thought about after game or before next game let me know and I will get them answered.]

The Lord Commander talks with the heroes on sharing knowledge about the cults. He is most disturbed when they mention the delegation was attacked by air. He tells the heroes that 5 of his men have gone missing and 2 of them so far have turned up naked and dead. He is afraid the air cult has robbed them and going around as Feathergale Knights . He mentions that he has a group already looking into that angle and hopefully will know more soon. [anyone skilled in Insight knows he is hiding something]

"I told you that Feathergale would try to aid the heroes of Red Larch in anyway it can. Here is something I got, that I can't act on right now. I have been informed of a hideout of the The Earth Cult …"

[everyone got a free insight check vs deception here. Even tho this isn't a lie, this is deception. He is telling 100% truth here, but he is hiding where he got this info. Since you all already know the truth there is a good chance you all would have passed (well maybe not Pappy's dice) a deception check with advantage. The Truth (or at least you suspect) is he was told this by "his queen Aerisi Kalinoth ". Josephus knows this name very well (please see Downtimes 1 and 5 if Rick forgot). The storyteller is continuing assuming you are sticking to the plan of not outing him.]

"… The place is called the Sacred Stone Monastery . What my spies have gathered is this place has been taken over by the The Earth Cult . There has been sightings of Mud Sorcerers entering this Monastery. If you learn anything about the Black The Earth Cult , please come back and share it with me so I can relay it to Waterdeep. They have taken a keen interest in this new cult rising since the attacks are growing more predominant."

Merosska draws a map for the heroes and sends them on their way. The Monastaery is hidden to the south east of the spire. It is roughly a full days walk. Once they arrived the heroes found a spot that they are far enough away to scout the monastery without being seen.

The heroes spend some time collecting information. During the day there seems to be more activity than at night. It is kind of hard to tell since most of the shutters on their windows are closed, but it is possible to see the glow of torches at night, and it seems very low on activity.

While setting up a place to camp, since they are going to be here for a little while, Barikhol takes a moment to give a teaching lesson to Armond . "Do ye smell that?"

Armond , "Aye. Is that a wine?"

Barikhol replies, "No, but I can see why ye think so. 'Tis brandy, but I doubt dey let der fruit distill long enough, which is what would make it smell like wine. Either dey are amateurs or dey are purposefully making it cheap."

Tyelknowle and Josephus went off to scout out the monastery. Ty counted 13 exterior windows that appeared locked, 4 doors, and possibly roof access. Josephus noticed they send guards on patrol every 45 minutes to 75 minutes.

The adventure will start with the heroes getting back together to tell each other what they have found.

Game 10 | Home | Game Notes | Game 11

Game 14

Game Day

Game Date: 02/11/17

In Play Date:: (10) Marpenoth 18, 1491;

TLDR

The heroes escaped from the Stone Monestary.
They had to run down the path to get to the waggon.
The Monks chased them down and used earth magic to try and stop them
The heroes got away
They are heading to the Dwarven Shrine up north.

Detailed Entry

The heroes go running out of monastery. Tyelknowle spills something on the floor as he is leaving and Joclyn is seen rolling her eyes. The heroes, Mud-Bloods , and seven slaves go running down the path towards the getaway wagon.

To the left of the path is a steep incline up a hill. To the right of the path is thick wooded area. The path is the fastest way to the wagon. Out of the monastery come an uncountable number of guards. A group of 20 – 30 take aim with arrows from the back. They are shooting at the party (15 including the slaves). Ander and Tyelknowle Cover the rear. Joclyn and Grimble protect the slaves. Otho is giving help to Armond , Barikhol , and Rowena who are injured and without their normal gear.

Ander and Ty yell up ahead, “Arrows! Take Cover!” Most people tried, the slaves were pushed towards the woods by Joclyn and Grimble took his shield and covered a couple of them. Only minor injuries were received from the arrows. After the first round of bolts the heroes crossed into the woods and the bowmen didn’t have a shoot.

Making it a little further down the hill the heroes were meet with a mob of guards and earth sorcerers.

{For the people who are actually interested how this works: Minion rules were established back in DnD1e. In DnD4e the developers thought it would be cool to reintroduce the idea of minions (apparently there was some extended rules in 3.5e that used minions too.). Unfortunately, even tho DnD4e had a lot of really cool attributes like this one, they missed the feel of DnD for many players. A lot of the cool things that are in 4e made it to 5e, but unfortunately this little gem missed the transition. Many players have toyed with bringing it over and the developers have talked about releasing a 5e version of the rule in an upcoming campaign book.

Minion rules for this game works as such: Instead of throwing a bunch of 1/8 CR creatures at the heroes, and the heroes taking down 1 bad guy at a time, you change it up to a little higher CR and record 1 stat for a group of creatures. Each group has 3 - 5 (or could be more) creatures in it. They act as a group and die as a group. So there is only one HP stat and one attack stat between all of them.

When the minion attacks they get a +X to their attack and damage. X = number in the mob – 1. So a mob with 4 people gain a +3 to attack and damage. When the Mob is damaged the mob is reduced by members based on how many hit points they have. So 20 HP with a 4-person mob has 5 HP each. When the mob is reduced their attacks and damage are reduced. So taking a 4-person mob (+3 attack/damage) to 2-person mob gives them (+1 attack/damage).

This helps the GM not have to keep track of SOOOOO many NPCs AND this allows the players to have those badass movie moments. I will not be using Minions all the time but when/if I do I will be very specific on who is a minion. }

They came sliding down the mountain and running out of the woods. Everyone held their own and many of them had to save the slaves. Ty and Joclyn caused a fire in the woods using their “Birthday Surprise” combo.

At one point some Earth Mages caused a rock slide and this almost killed the party. This did kill many of the Earth Guards.

{I made a mistake here and realized it when I saw people dropping. I tried correcting it at the game and it kind of looked sloppy. Sorry. My mistake was I rolled from the deadly table instead of the setback table. I just halved the roll to meet with the kind of damage I expected to see, but I should have rerolled from the setback table instead.}

Otho was swept away by the slide. He got pulled under the rocks and Ander yelled out. Joclyn looked over that direction and ran over there pulling up rocks along with Barikhol . She scooped up Otho and started running up rock by rock as they were still sliding down the hill.

They finally got to the other side and continued fighting and running down the hill. After the mob was taken out, the heroes kept running for their wagon.

//Cut Scene\\

Four archer monks come running over the rock slide as the heroes already made it through. They get over there in enough time to watch the last of their monks get taken down. One of them starts to run forward when another grabs him. “Don’t worry Jock and her crew won’t let them get anywhere. She should be ambushing them any time now.

5 rounds ago:

Jock is leading her crew of earth monks out the back after the heroes. They have practiced this 100 times. They can bend the ground to start having trees fall on them. They will make it to the lower part of the path by running along the mountain top. The others will slow them down so they can get into position. It is rare anyone makes it all the way to Jocks crew. Along with Jocks crew is a hill giant. They start running through the garden when… SLIP! Their feet go sliding out from under them and they crash into a wall.

Jock looks back, "Trip bearings. Who the hell…" Jock looks up remembering something.

The hill giant comes barreling around the corner as Jock and her crew are yelling “NO! NO! STOP!”, but it was too late. The Hill giant loses footing and goes crashing right into Jock and her crew.

From the outside of the monastery you can see dust shaking off one of the exterior walls right after a loud thud.

//End Cut Scene\\

Ridding away on the wagon the heroes discuss where to go. Someone says that the Dwarven Shrine is just to the north. The Heroes point out the Dwarves were not helpful to them, but they did at least make accommodations for a place to rest for the night. Grimble thought he may be able to put in a good word.

Game 31.1 (Armonds Story) | Home | Game Notes | Game 15

Game 12&13

Game Day

Game Date: 1/14/2017

In Play Date:: (10) Marpenoth 18, 1491 ;

TLDR

• Ty recruits the Mud-Bloods to rescue the heroes.

• The Heroes, locked in a earth prison, are undergoing torture to try and be convinced to join the Earth Cult

• The Mud-Bloods have to fight some scary Orogs and an Orc

• They free the Heroes and some slaves

• They are now running form the Monastery being chased by others in the order.

Detailed Entry

At the Mud-blood camp, people in the crowd start noticing the two visitors talking to Joclyn . A couple more approached. These two seemed to recognize one of the visitors, Ty.

Ty explained the problem about how his friends were captured and he needs their help. Joclyn and the Mud-Bloods were eager to help, but they themselves were in a bit of a survival problem.

Joclyn said she will go and two others who knew Ty volunteered, but Joclyn ordered others to say with the camp, they take priority. They set off the next morning.

Back at the Earth Prison:

The three were locked up in a cell. There were two other cells with prisoners in them. Armond thought he may have enough strength to escape. He tried porting out, but stepping outside the prison he landed in what felt like quicksand.

The sand drug him back through the rocks and back into the cell. It was extremely painful and he almost suffocated.

"Heh Heh Heh Heh." a large creature said. "This place was designed by Earth Mages. Good luck getting past their traps."

Hours turned into days, Days turned into Weeks, Weeks turned in to forever. The monsters didn't give time for the prisoners to recover from wounds or rest. They took shifts mining paths. They would be taken near a lava pit and would have to lay there till they would pass out from the pain. They would be beaten, whipped, made to suffocate in quicksand, and more.

Hellenrae would visit the heroes. She would try and convince them to join the Earth order. "Look, I don't want to kill you down here in the mines. This is no place for you. Serve me and I can make your lives so much better. Rowena , you already have Earth Magic in you. I can help you control it better. Armond , Wouldn't you rather have your powers not from a source that will defeat you in the end? Barikhol , your monk training is nearly as matched as mine. I can teach you way more than your Genasi Master could. Take the Earths Promise and I will free you from this cell."

Armond spat on her. Hellenrae was pissed. The heroes could see her trying to compose herself. "Fine. Let me know when you're ready."

The pain didn't let up. Rowena got to the point where she couldn't take it anymore. It has been said that sometimes when people are in captivity, their brains shut down. They go somewhere else. Rowena was visited by Odert . The bard dwarf living in her consciousness. "Lass. Let me take over for a little bit. I can handle this." Rowena trying to protect him acted strong, but Odert reminder her, "We share the same mind. I can see right through you. I want to help. When I can't do it anymore, you take over."

Rowena finally agreed and was whisked away to Castle Keep. Here she was at home, but something was different. The library wasn't clean, it didn't have the right smell. It sounded weird even. Then she saw something else in the library. No one else has ever been in her head world before.

She chased down the creature and found it was a fox. It was lost and scared. Rowena noticed the fox's ears. They matched her ears perfectly. She reached up to touch her ears and in the real world Odert did the same thing. Except when she and Odert touched her ears, they were different somehow.

Rowena knew the fox was dying and she also knew there was nothing she could do. So she just held it and kept telling it. "It's ok. It's ok. I got you."

Odert sniffed and scratched his eyes before trying to get a few minutes of sleep.

{If any of you wondered why I didn't find time to type last games notes. I didn't want to relive this moment.}

One day a slave was thrown into the cell. He looked at the heroes and started to laugh. The party didn't recognize him at first. He spoke in a deep voice. "Of course you're here. You campions of Red Larch can't keep your noses out of other people's business. I see your dwarf friend is still alive."

At this point the heroes have all recognized him. Larrakh , the earth mage from Red Larch . He looks like he has seen better days. "Where is your human and your elf?" he said smugly up to Armond .

Armond unloaded what little strength he had and started punching Larrakh over and over in the face. Barakhol and Odert gave each other a look before finally pulling Armond up before he killed Larrakh . Armond would have pulled away before Larrakh died, but Larrakh doesn't need to know that.

The mud-bloods and Ty's friend Grimble traveled back to the Stone Monastery. After scouting the place they picked the lock on the back door and traveled into the garden.

The garden was full of statues. Some of them angelic like, but others of all different races. The statues were too real, and a couple heroes think they may have once been alive.

Trying to escape this room is when the heroes got attacked by two gargoyles. After dispensing of them, they snuck into a room where they found a man working by candle light.

After surprising him by a knife to the back, the man pleaded for his life. "Look! I am here against my will. They use me to study magic. I don't want to do that for these monsters! Please don't kill me. Just let me be and I will pretend I never saw you."

The heroes chose not to buy that and asked him where they keep the prisoners. The man drew them a map. They also took him with them.

Down in the stairs they entered a room where Grimble could sense the undead. The Mud-bloods got ready and tore into the room. The zombies were no match for this crew.

"What is on the other side of this door?" one of the half-elves asked.

"It is their pet Umber Hulk. He guards the things they collect." the scared man replies.

Ty took one of his pitons and make sure that door wasn't going to open.

Otho took a look at the door leading into the cave and informed the rest of the group. This door is stuck. It is going to be loud when we open it.

Ty casted a silence spell. "ok, try now." he mouthed. Everyone was already looking around since all the sound went out of the cave. They looked at Ty who was grinning with his new trick.

"Cool." Joclyn mouthed and nodded at Otho and Ander to bust open the door. Ty signed in thieves cant to let him and Otho scout ahead.

Going out into the hall they ran across these snake like creatures with tentacles and they also ran across these fungi things with tentacles. They also found a Orog guarding some slaves.

Ty went back to let the others know. The group objected "We are losing our luck down here. Eventually someone will come by." They decided to sneak down so they can come around the back.

Grimble came out and tightened up his equipment so he wouldn't make too much noise sneaking through these caves. When he went to pick up his shield, he dropped it and it did that metal rattling over and over as it spins to a stop on the ground. "You think they heard that?"

The door across from them came flying open and an Orog screamed something in Ogre as an arrow flew strait at him. It hit him and they started a fight.

In this fight there was 3 orogs and 1 ogre. Grimble charged to blocked the door and the Orog kicked him back to get into the hall. The Ogre squeezed through the door and was swinging his massive club. The other two Orogs ran around back and Otho had to hide. He snuck around the other side barely missing the other Orog who was guarding the slaves.

They were running around the outside to flank the heroes from the side. Also, they couldn't fit through the door. This is a design flaw of the dungeon and should be reconsidered while they have slaves to do the work.

The heroes continued to fight the Ogre and the Orog. Otho snuck around and attacked the Orog that was following up the rear. He hit him twice and leaped back and ducked out of sight. Otho threw a rock and the Orog followed the sound. Otho jumped out again and stabbed him twice, but didn't get away this time. The Orog knocked him off balance with his great axe. Otho took a quick Jab at the Orog and disappeared into the cave again. "How does this little man do this?" he questioned in Ogre.

The rest of the heroes took up against the flank, finishing off the Ogre and the Orog just in time. Grimble and Joclyn were holding off the Orogs when they were hit by a couple unlucky hits. Ty was there to pull them back and get them up to health.

Otho appeared behind the Orog that he kept pestering and placed his dagger right through his spine. With a pop, the Orog went down.

Ander snuck into the Ogre's room to find the key after finding it he ran down to the slaves pin. He freed them and said "We need to go."

The pins next to the one where he saved the others had other slaves in them. Ander looked at them and thought, "There isn't time." He threw them the keys and started to go.

Barakhol said "No, we can't just leave them."

Rowena was already running over to retrieve the keys and open the cells.

Ander rolling his eyes, "Hurry up."

The slaves were weak and tired, but they ran as best they could.

Ty ran and got the other slaves that were mining in the cave and they ran too.

Once they got outside, they made a break for the tree line. From behind them they heard "They went this way! Get them!"

Game 15 | Home | Game Notes | Game 27

Leokas Backstory

Stories

Leokas was born to Norven and Mara Greycastle in a rather quiet village on the western side of "country/town". Norven made a decent living running their moderately sized farm, and was able to provide a pretty good life for his family. As Leokas grew older he helped out on the family farm and held various part time jobs in town to earn play money; but as most young adults often do, he began to dream of more, of travel and exploring faraway lands. When he was 18 Leokas joined the army and he got his wish; throughout his time in the military he traveled far and wide and met many different people of all cultures and backgrounds. After many years of service Leokas had reached the rank of major and as an officer had many men under his command.

One day during a particularly nasty battle Leokas and a small group of his men were caught off guard and captured. They tortured and beat him for what felt like weeks, but with the physical exhaustion and lack of sleep who could tell how long it had really been. One day seemingly out of the blue they cleaned him up, dressed him back in his armor and dropped him off  somewhere close to his army. After waiting for them to leave, he removed his blindfold and gathered his bearings, starting off in the direction he felt his army would be in, he traveled for days before he was eventually found, dehydrated and malnourished. They took him back in and patched him up and even gave him a medal for being wounded in combat, and being the sole survivor.   (Spoiler)

Shortly after returning to the army Leokas decided it was best for him to just leave the military. His superiors granted him an early retirement at rank, and after 10 years of service they sent him off with honors including his armor and uniform.

Months had passed since his capture and release and yet Leokas could still never forgive himself for the loss of his fellow soldiers’ lives. Leokas wandered aimlessly for months trying to drink and whore away the torment and shame he felt inside, but nothing eased his suffering. His uniform tattered and wasted in countless drunken brawls and nights slept in the gutters of whatever random town he found himself in for the evening. He even fell as far as to pawn his armor to fund this downward spiraling behavior. With no money, no place to stay, and barely the clothes he had on his back, stumbling drunk he found himself at the steps to a temple of Pelor. Half crawling his way inside he made it to the alter and began cursing the gods for his current lot in life, when in the middle of his tears and anguish he felt as if a warm, powerful, yet comforting voice spoke to him. This voice, admonishing, "Why are you making such a scene in my temple?  If you really want relief from your internal struggle, stand up and stop weeping like a woman. If you want your life to have meaning and purpose again, then serve me, become a guardian of the weak, standing for good and light. Become one of my clerics and do good in my name."

At this revelation Leokas was stunned; why would someone as powerful as a god even care what happened to him, he was no worshipper, he had never considered himself a righteous man. Nevertheless Leokas vowed at that moment to do as he was asked, he vowed to become a shield for those who had none and to do good and spread the influence of Pelor.

Leokas spent the next few months praying, and studying the holy texts and working with others at that temple.

(Storyteller Edit)

One such man went by the name of Wyer . Wyer was a skilled cleric of Pelor and he saw something in Leokas . Wyer offered to train Leokas . They trained with weapons and cleric spells, Wyer didn’t want Leokas to go out there fighting in the name of Pelor unprepared.

(/Storyteller Edit)

Applying the determination he once showed in the military he quickly became a rather skilled cleric. He worked hard in the temple, and found all sorts of odd jobs around town; and he saved every last bit of it, as he had plans to track down his old armor, and attempt to restore it to its former glory and wear it as a proud soldier should.

(Storyteller Edit)

Wyer and Leokas was sparing. They got into an intense match when other clerics and workers stopped doing what they were doing to watch. The new recruits were awestruck by Wyer and Leokas combat skills. Leokas finally made an attack that made Wyer lose his footing and Wyer was laying on the ground, with his hands up yielding the fight.

They were toweling off and Wyer was talking to Leokas about his journey. Wyer was talking about the dangers that Leokas will face out there. He also recited a few passages for Leokas to remember. Wyer reached into his bag and pulled out something that was wrapped in paper. “Here. Take this with you. Don’t open it now. It isn’t a big deal. I wanted you to have something to remember your training. You will do great things. I know it.”

(/Storyteller Edit)

After saving what he estimated he would need for food, and travel, as well as what it might cost to buy this armor back from the hands of whomever currently held it; he sought out the shopkeeper where he pawned it. Arriving at the shop, he inquired about the armor, expecting to have to pay the man with coin for the name of the person it was sold to; when he was pleasantly surprised to find that the merchant still had the armor. Turns out that even though at the time it held no honor for Leokas when he pawned it, most people in the area still respected the sight of a ranking officer, and found it in bad taste that such a merchant would be trying to sell a suit of armor such as this. What seemed like a pretty good deal to the merchant thinking he could make a quick and tidy profit on the armor, wound up draped on a mannequin with little more than disdain from the patrons of his shop. Lowering the price, to no avail, he finally tucked the armor away in the back to possibly sell for scrap one day, as it seemed keeping it in the storefront did more to harm his business than gain him profit. He sold it back to Leokas for the same amount originally given, happy to be rid of the thing.

Leokas now with his armor returned, found himself with a good bit more coin than he had expected, and he decided to use some of it to polish up and repair the armor and shield, and even had the emblem on the shield changed to that of a blazing sun, the symbol of his new found patron. He gave half of what was left as an offering to the temple and set out once again, this time with renewed vigor and a new purpose in life. Deciding it had been a while since he had seen his folks, he set his path towards that of his home town, eager to share the news of his newfound purpose serving Pelor.

Spoiler:

The enemy grew bored with beating him and his fellow soldiers, and had so far gained no actionable information from anyone. In an effort to get someone to talk, or just for sheer entertainment....who really knows; they began coming up with creative ways to execute the prisoners.....

One night after hearing the screams, and eventual silence of those captured with him, Leokas heard the fateful sounds of heavy feet approach his cell. Leokas heard the ominous sound of the lock being opened, and the faint chuckle that escaped the mouth of his captor. Blindfolded, starving, beaten and bruised, he knew this was the end; the internal panic set in, "I can't die yet... I don't want to die ...I... I ..." sobbing, he found the words left his lips without thought, "I'll talk, I'll talk.... what do you want to know, please just don't kill me."

Hours later Leokas had given the enemy battle plans, troop movements, and numbers; almost everything he knew.  As the next few days went by, something was different, he was being given water and stale bread, and the beatings had stopped. One day he heard what sounded like a celebration nearby, there were lots of loud voices, music, laughter and cheers. Again, the door to his cell was unlocked. With a different, rather jovial chuckle the guard escorted him to his feet and guided him out of his cell. They must have walked for some time and eventually they found their way outside, Leokas could feel the cool breeze, which at this point felt great on his bruised skin. He was led a bit further, and then stopped, he was forced to kneel, and then panic set back in; his blindfold was removed, and after his eyes focused he could see that he was outside under the moonlight and stars.

Leokas found himself in front of a high ranking enemy officer, the celebration all around him quieted as the commander stood up from his seat. The commander walked over to him, looked him over, and then called to one of the guards; "What is this? Why do you bring him to me like this? Clean him up, give him some proper clothes... he is our honored guest after all" Those last words, dripping with sarcastic contempt found deep purchase within Leokas . At that moment he realized, this was a victory celebration, the enemy must have won a great battle today. They cleaned him up, gave him fresh clothing, and then they gave him a fake crown; they paraded him all around the camp, mockingly praising him for his aid. They poured their drinks on his head, pretended to drunkenly trip him, and forcefully bump into him; all the while the guards behind him kept him at a steady pace. As the night came to a close, he was led off to a separate area, and led into a rather large and plush tent. Inside the tent the enemy commander approached him again with that horrible smile, and gave him a hug that made Leokas ' skin crawl. "Have you had fun tonight, friend ?" there was that word again. Still grinning the commander turned to someone behind him gesturing to his left; "We have one more thing for you... a parting gift , as it were"

A woman was there, that Leokas hadn't noticed before, she wore strange robes and had odd tattoos on the parts of her arms that he could see; then his focus shifted, to the object she was carrying. A short rod, with the symbol of the enemy tribe at the end of it. As she approached she started muttering words Leokas didn't understand; and he could see that the tip of this rod, where the symbol was began glowing with an unnatural light. As she got close he felt the tight grip of the guards as they stepped up behind him and grabbed his arms holding him firmly in place; the commander moved forward and tore open the shirt he was wearing. The woman then pressed the symbol into his chest, just left of center, right where his heart would be.

Leokas hadn't felt pain like this before, not even during the torture; his vision closed in and his body clenched so tight he couldn't breathe, and then it was done; the woman removed the rod, the guards relaxed their grip, and the commander stood over him, with this smug, pleased look on his face.

Leokas wasn't sure if the pain had stopped or his body was just numb, but the branding process was complete. The commander spoke once more, though this time his head was so fuzzy from the ordeal Leokas had to strain to hear him, as the commander sounded like he was far off. "We give you this gift as a reminder, heh... even amongst our people cowardice is despised." He then spit on Leokas , calling him a traitor to his own people. "We will let him return to his own, let him live out his pathetic life... if he can" At that point a spike of sharp pain washed over the back of Leokas ' head, and everything faded to black.

Leokas woke up to a bouncing sensation, and a splitting headache, he tried to reach for his head, but found his hands were once again bound, and he was again blindfolded. A short bit of travel from that point they stopped, he was unceremoniously tossed onto the ground, rolled over onto his stomach and his bounds were cut with a knife. "Stay there until we're gone, or you won't ever make it back home.." He heard the men saddle their horses and leave; he waited another hour, after the sound of their hooves could no longer be heard, and then he crawled to his feet, stood, and removed the blindfold. No enemy was to be found, he was dressed in the armor he was captured in, and he could tell that the wound on his chest was dressed and bandaged. The enemy even left him his shield, but were smart enough to not arm him; not that he could do much fighting in the state he was in.

Beaten and broken, he aimlessly wandered in one direction without food or water for days until he finally collapsed, just as he was spotted by another human. They immediately rushed to him to offer aid, and as they lifted Leokas up to his feet, supporting him under his shoulder, he barely heard "Sir, are you ok..." before passing out yet again.

Leokas awoke, on a bed... a warm, comfy bed, even a cool breeze was in the air which carried the faint, pleasant smell of food cooking on a fire nearby.  A tray of food and water sat on a small bedside table next to him, and he could even tell that he had been washed and clothed in a clean robe. He quickly devoured the food and water and then slowly slid himself out of bed. Walking towards the door of the tent he pulled the flap to the side and was immediately greeted by a guard standing watch. "Sir!" as the man snapped to attention, "I've been instructed to tell you to wait here; if you need anything you can ask Reginald and he will get it for you." Leokas glanced to his left and saw another guard, also standing at attention looking his way; while the first guard took off at a determined pace. It was at this point that Leokas recognized the uniform, it was the uniform of his army, "..I’m back!"  and then remorse and survivors guilt washed over him, and he felt a ball of self-loathing in the pit of his stomach. Leokas gave a halfhearted solute to the soldier on watch outside the tent, and turned around and went back inside.

In the following days, Leokas was debriefed, given some more time to recover, and then an award ceremony was held in his honor where he was given an award for bravery, and being wounded in battle. He put on a face, and acted the humble soldier, all the while that pit in his stomach grew. Weeks later, as they were preparing him to step back in to his role as an officer, they were reviewing all of the intelligence and details of recent battles, and plans for upcoming ones, when Leokas was told of a horrible loss, a massive, surprise defeat with the loss of thousands of soldiers that set their campaign back months. He realized, this was right around when he was captured, this was even a troop movement he knew of; although he wasn't really supposed to know, as it wasn't his battalion, but that of a fellow officer and close friend, that let slip one night after one too many drinks, that he had been given a secret mission to ambush the enemy. As the details of this defeat were described, the blood drained from his body, "....we are still investigating how they knew.... it was a complete loss, none survived...... current theory holds that somehow they got divine insight from that unholy witch companion he has...." Leokas subconsciously scratched at the branded mark on his chest; catching himself, he excused himself from the war room and retired to his chambers.

He found no sleep that night with the thought of his friend losing his life playing in his head; and it was all his fault. Leokas sat up and went over to the wash basin, grabbed a knife and tore at the brand, trying to cut it off or disfigure it, both to bury the shame and to keep more knowledgeable eyes from seeing it and asking deeper questions, the kind that Leokas would rather not answer. Bloodied he looked in the mirror, it was done, the scar was mangled and half cut off, "now I just need to clean it up and bandage it and I won't ever have to tell anyone what..."  at that moment he watched in the mirror, as the scarred, mangled, patch of flesh on his chest, grew itself back together. He stared in disbelief, as the brand was once more, there before him, made whole; and he could hear again that smug laughter of the enemy commander "... a gift ..."     "Fuck!"

(Storyteller Edit)

Leokas looked at the branding . The center was a long stretched oval, like a tall egg. The edges were like an upside down tringle made of a stack of bricks. The oval and the edges were the same shade, almost purple, but the rest of the middle was black as the night sky.

(/Storyteller Edit)

He quickly cleaned up the knife and area around the basin, and then poured himself a strong drink. Two bottles later he lay passed out across the bed.

Within the next few weeks, Leokas petitioned the high command for early retirement, stating his self-confidence was shaken while captured, and he didn't feel as though he could be a fit commander if hesitation entered into his judgement. He could tell high command was unhappy with the request, but they must have taken pity on him, as his request was granted and he was allowed to retire, at rank, and " honorably ".

Prev | Home | Character Backstories | Armond Backstory

Barikhol and Leokas

Stories

Barikhol and Leokas

I had just finished a nice batch of Fire Mead, and was expecting to have some great road side sales, given the fact there were lots of travelers for the Harvesttide festival.  Just about dusk, this cleric of Pelor came shambling in, and I do mean shambling.  He had days of road grime coating him, a bit of blood on this clothes, and was in dire need of a bath.  This guy also seemed to have a chip on his shoulder; just seemed pissed off at the world.

He bought his first round out of a fat coin pouch and chose to drink a mug of Forefather’s Fire Mead.  I was impressed, not many humans can drink a mug without crying for milk, but it seemed to fit his mood.  Now he really looked like he could spit fire.  HAHA!

He gave me a sob story about doing something that would offended Pelor, and was upset that he was put in a bad position where he had to make a hard choice.  I didn’t pay much attention, just kept selling him more to drink.  After several mugs, he got quiet and completive.

About that time, two fellas reigned in their horses aside my forest brewery.  One was a tall thin fellow in a black robe with runic embroidery, and the other was a short mean lookin’ bastard with a big blade.  He looked like he could handle it too.  Didn’t bother me none, I had more customers (and ain’t afeared of a couple of rough looking fellas).

They approached me and asked for an ale, and I let them know that it’d cost em a silver for the two.  He said  "Zyliath the Great shouldn’t have to pay for this swill". Well, I never did like anyone insulting my ale, so I just crossed my arms and stared at him.  That made Zyliath’s face turn red!  But he paid up.

Bout that time this cleric piped up and said “Zyliath, I know of a Zyliath.  He swindles good folk out of hard earned coin for paltry and useless magics.  He is a charlatan really.  Also has a short, ugly bodyguard by the name of Sophus Dahl, who likes to torment folks weaker than him.  Might you be that Zyliath and Sophus?”

Now that was funny!  I thought the skinny guy was going to have a heart attack and his face turned real red like he was chokin’ and then he started muttering.   I thought I would join in the fun and added “This fella can’t be Zyliath cuz Zyliath sounds like a she elf name”.

I guess that was Zyliath, because out of the sleeve of his robe, he pulled a short wand.  About the same time, the short fella unsheathed his sword.

The short bodyguard didn’t get very far with that blade before the cleric, standing up, spun around and caught him in the throat with the flat edge of his shield. Sophus’ face turned a deep red almost purple, dropping to his knees and losing his grip on the sword, he now clutched at his throat with both hands spitting and coughing.

Cleric: “I really can’t stand people like you. Life is already tough enough without assholes like you causing trouble.”

Zyliath momentarily caught off guard by this display, regained his focus and turned to point the wand at the Monk that just insulted him; only to find the monk was no longer standing there.  After the split second of confusion, Zyliath felt a new sensation, weightlessness, and yet, at the same time… the world moved around him. He lie there on the ground making a wheezing sucking noise, trying to catch his breath after having his legs swept clean out from under him, with his wand just a few feet out of reach after tumbling from his grip on impact.

Cleric: “I’ve had a rough week and just wanted to relax and enjoy this mans’ fine ale, and you two had to go and spoil it.”

Grabbing the bodyguard by his collar the cleric leaned into him a bit:

 “I’m pretty sure there’s a small reward for you, and I certainly don’t feel like seeing any more blood spilt for a while, so you get to live another day.”

As soon as he finished those words he clocked Sophus in the back of the head with the handle of his mace knocking him unconscious.

Zyliath seeing this all happen so quickly, and being on the flat of his back, decided he no longer needed a drink and as quickly as he could mounted his horse and sped off.

Standing straight again the cleric looked over to the monk.

Cleric: “Nice moves…. Name’s Leokas ”

Holding out his hand awaiting a handshake and gesturing with a slight tilt of his head.

Leokas : “What do you want to do with this one?”

Barikhol grasped Leokas’s wrist in a warrior’s handshake.  “Name’s Barikhol” he said.  “There is a Waterdavian outpost not far from here.  Let’s truss up Sophus there, toss em on the back of his horse and take him in.  You can keep any bounty on him.  We can sell the horse and tack and split the profit.”.

“You got some moves yourself by the way Leokas.  Coulda been a monk of Illmater; ya woulda fit right in.  By the way, Illmater teaches one to suffer for others and defend the helpless.  You did a good thing here with these goblin spawned whoresons, so I wouldn’t worry about offending Pelor.  Surely your deeds outweigh any bad dat may’ve been done”.  “I’m glad to have met ye, and would be proud to call ye friend.”

Prev | Home | Character Collaborative Adventures | Armond Collaborative Adventure

Believers

Overview

The Believers guard the moving stones, and make sure no one disturbs the Delvers, who are entombed down here. The Believers watch the moving stones carefully, because it’s a bad sign when they move, and they have to figure out what it means to advert danger.

They were a secret group that was lead by Larrakh. Dornen and Ilmeth did kill the people found in the cave. Grund was caught, but he was not actually the one who killed them. Grund was manipulated by the Believers that he was helping by trying to hide the bodies.

Elak Dornen: The de facto leader. He is stern and inflexible.Sent to Waterdeep to serve trial.
Ilmeth Waelvur: Hard-drinking and sullen. Sent to Waterdeep to serve trial.
Ulhro Luruth: Runs a Tannery in Red Larch. He was interrigated by the Heroes to give up the Believers.
Grund: This goofy half-orc is a sort of hired goon for The Believers.
Baragustas: He was one of the original Believers. He oversaw that the rituals the group performed.
Rotharr: He is known for the day of the collapse. His son, Braelen, was going through the rituals of becoming a Believer. Tyelknowle caught him and his son sneaking out of the tunnels.

Never found out:

Albaeri Mellikho (page 28): She is jovial and a "whirlwind".

Sword Coast | Home | Up | Active Character List

Game 15

Overview

Description: The heroes should learn more about the cults from the shrine.

Challenges

The heroes are currently traveling to the Vale of Dancing Waters

During the trip Joclyn will talk to Ty

- Once we drop you off I need to take Otho and Ander to Waterdeep. Father Franz has another mission for us.

- I am not sure of the mission. When I was healing I would do some task for him every now and then. Once I returned to the Mud-Bloods I continued working for him. He is a good man. I feel I still owe him… and you.

Interrogating Larrakh

- Larrakh will work with the heroes ONLY IF someone guarantees his freedom. They will need to convince him.

- Larrakh will tell them he used to be a part of the Cult of the Black Earth, but his ideas had him removed. The cult wants to bring about the end of the world. With these powers we could control the world. I tried to get them to see reason, but I only was able to recruit 6 men, who you all put down.

- The caves of the Sacred Stone Monastery go much deeper.

At the Vale

 When the heroes arrive at the Vale of Dancing Waters they are greeted again by Thorke the Dwarvin cleric.

“You all Again? I will give you a room out here, but that is the best I will do. You are not permitted in the Vale.”

Information:

They know something of the Cults. The attack on Beliard about a month ago by Bastian . They are still recovering. We sent a couple healers and workers up there to try and do what we can.
The earth cult has been kidnapping more and more people for slave work.
The water cult and the air cult went to war near Wormford
Halli is a dwarf from the Mirabar Delegation

Back at Red Larch

The heroes will be attacked by Grund . He will be super excited to see them. “Many thought you were ded.”
Wyer will also see them. He will be excited to know they are still alive. “I have been keeping up with your tab at Swinging Sword .” He will want to know what has happened to them.
Everyone in town will be very excited to see them.
Stannor will be looking for his horse and wagon.
Justran will serve them in when they arrive at the Healm at Highsun.

While in Red Larch

Armond will get a messenger that someone is waiting for him at the town’s border. (Kid from the trials came to get armond)
When Armond gets out there he will see Harburk standing out there staring at someone.
It will be a necromancer with two zombies chained to his back.
He will pull back the hood and say. “Are you Armond the one who killed my son?” Oreioth (The Lord of Lance Rock ).
Do you have the dagger of Velsharron?
That dagger was never his own.
I will return in one month, please have the knife for me.
Where is my son?
Harburk says: “We buried him. South of here, near (gives some landmark).”

Also While in Red Larch at the end of the TenDay

Two, very attractive women come into town on a caravan.
The caravan is a known caravan that travels the long road, from Mirabar down to Waterdeep.
They come into the Tavern and after a few drinks they say, “We need help. Our ship was hijacked and our crew was killed. The fuckers had a symbol that looks like this (and shows the symbol of the Cult of the Crushing Wave). Anyone know where we can get help or do we need to travel all the way down to Waterdeep?”
If we are to recruit you: You get half of the bounty, we will give you information where we were attack and where they were heading. Deal?
Where were you attacked? We were just about to enter into the Sumber Hills. When they attacked.
Info: These dicks were sorcerers. They could control the water.
Look, our ship is propabaly gone, but there was something on there that we really would like back.

Prev | Home | Game 15 | Next

Tyelknowle Collaborative Adventure

Stories

Heroes:: Tyelknowle , Josephus , Armond

Tyelknowle walked slowly but surely along the long dusty road. He reflected on the events that had brought him to this, his first pilgrimage. He hadn’t realized how much he longed for the open road and maybe even the woodlands. It seemed like a lifetime ago since he and his family had been free. Frequently at night he would dream about saving them, but he had no real idea where to start. Even if he knew where they had been captured it had been decades and he couldn’t be sure they were there. He had to trust that Tymora would guide the way if it was to be. Tyelknowle ’s keen eyes spotted a person running towards him on the normally lonely road and he was instantly on guard. He glanced around noting likely hiding spots but couldn’t make out any good ambush locations. Regardless, he pulled out his rapier and patted the daggers he kept up sleeves just to be sure they would slide if he needed them. The runner turned out to be a young human, probably early adolescent as humans judged years, his clothes were torn and he was running in fear, something Tyelknowle was very familiar with. The young man fell to his knees begging for help. His family had been set upon by bandits. There were at least five of them and his father was already wounded, maybe dead. Tyelknowle reassured the young human that he would help, though he wasn’t sure what he could do against so many. Perhaps he could wait till they left and try to heal the survivors. Regardless, he made his way to the spot in the woods. He quickly outpaced the boy who was calling out for him to wait. Tyelknowle try to shush him but simply decided to hide in the woods and sneak up to observe the scene. Sure enough there were five brutish looking thugs, a man laying on the ground bleeding, a woman struggling with something, also hurt but conscious and another boy, much younger than the runner, crying over the man’s body. They obviously needed help but so did Tyelknowle if he wanted to be of any use. “Tymora, I need a little luck here…”

Being that he was alone (other than the young human he just encountered), Tyelknowle knew that he had to either fight or scare off the bandits on his own. With the element of surprise and the Luck of Tymora on his side, he drew his weapon and prepared to charge in like a lightening quick tornado of death when suddenly the broad head of an arrow burst through the back of the bandit! The force of the arrow's impact threw the bandit backwards towards Tyelknowle 's hiding place. The bandit, not comprehending what just happened, died with a look of utter shock and bewilderment on his face. In a flash, another human was upon the bandits sweeping his glaive through a second bandit. The first human, with the bow, was taking aim at a third bandit, when suddenly the bandit grabbed the boy's mother and held her in front of him with a wicked looking dagger at her throat. The bandit's back was to Tyelknowle . "Drop the bow! You and your friend leave or I'll kill her!!"

FLASHBACK: Weeks prior, Armond and Josephus were commissioned to stop a band of bandits that have been attacking caravans along the highway. Since then, they had been tracking down the group of bandits responsible for the slew of robberies. Every time Armond and Josephus thought that had caught up to the bandits they had already moved camp a night or two before.

THAT AFTERNOON: Wearily Armond and Josephus followed the bandit’s tracks through the woods. As they stopped to rest, they heard a commotion. As they went to investigate, low and behold, they had found the bandits, still in the midst of another robbery. Armond and Josephus also noticed that an elf had stalked up on the bandits. Seeing that he was a little outnumbered, Armond and Josephus decide to even the odds. Moving closer Josephus could see that the bandits were starting to get frustrated with an older woman. They assumed she was the mother and was refusing to give the bandits her wedding ring telling them it was from her mother. Fearing for the family's safety, Armond and Josephus had to act quickly. Thanks to their military training they made short work on a plan to take down the bandits. Josephus lined up his longbow and let the arrow fly. The arrow hit true as its broad head drilled straight through one of the unsuspecting bandits throwing him back. At that moment Armond sprang into action and like a flash, was upon another bandit with his glaive finding its mark cleaving him asunder. From where Armond had come from, Josephus had already knock a second arrow and had a bead on a third bandit. But they made a mistake. They allowed one of the bandits to get too close to one of the innocents.

The young elf hadn’t been a cleric long, but he recognized Tymora’s Luck when he saw it. Stepping out with speed and confidence he slipped one of his daggers from its wrist sheath and neatly slid it up into the bandit’s neck, the sweet spot, where there was no skull to keep the keen blade from piercing the brain. Death was instant. Tyelknowle did not like to kill, but he knew how if he had to. This human would be standing before Kelemvor. The bandit and woman fell forward and Tyelknowle bent over to assist her. This saved his life as a fourth bandit swung an axe which would have sliced the elf’s spine. Instead, it hit a tree and a glaive removed the arms from the man before he could pull it out. He stared dumbly at his bleeding stubs while the skilled halbardier continued the momentum and crushed his skull with the heavy butt of his weapon.

The elf looked up, eyes wide. “Oh yes, there are at least five…” The archer was already tracking the last bandit who was smart enough to realize he wanted no part of the skilled and coordinated soldiers. An arrow flew catching him in the leg.

“I surrender. Please, mercy. I give up.” The bandit was yelling. Armond was racing toward him and pinned him beneath his blade.

“We were supposed to stop them. Was that dead or alive?” he asked his comrade.

“Dead makes it easier.” The archer was walking over to the bandit. The wound wasn’t bad and he would likely live, but should he.

The elf was tending to the family but grew worried at the tone of their conversation, “Please! He has given up. I can save the family. This man should pay for his crimes but there is no need to murder a prisoner.” Tyelknowle was tense. He called upon the blessings of Tymora to knit and mend the wounds of the father. His breathing was stable and his bleeding stopped. However, the elf knew that when humans had it in them to kill, they could be bloodthirsty. And it was possible these were just more thieves, although their story of a bounty rang true.

“I don’t mind sparing a prisoner, but these bandits have done terrible things why should we complicate matters by keeping one alive to have to carry with us?” The humans were obviously warriors of some caliber and Tyelknowle didn’t like the idea of antagonizing his benefactors. He had to think, was this a test from his god?

“Uh… You’ve been after them… searching yes? For some time, yes? I’m guessing you’ve not found their hideout... with all their loot?” This caught their attention. The most likely way to sway a human, mention money. “This one can guide you. Please, just show mercy.” The elf had walked over to the group and was unconsciously standing close enough to the bandit to try to help, although there wasn’t much he could do.

The two made eye contact and almost immediately smiled and nodded. “That is brilliant. Ok ‘buddy’, you take us to your hideout and you get to live long enough to see whatever justice the locals have for you. Just don’t make it harder on us and you walk… err limp out of this.” The bandit, sensing his life hung on a whim nodded his earnest and eager agreement.

“Thank you. Tymora will bless you for this. My name is Tyelknowle , but humans often call me Ty. I will bury these poor souls and see to the care of this family before I continue on my pilgrimage. Even the wicked deserve their rest, and it helps to cut down on the undead. I hope one day I can repay your timely aid. Tymora willing, we will meet again.

The three parted ways and the young elf felt he had just taken a big step along his god’s quest. He also sensed he had not seen the last of those two, Tymora willing.

Rowena Collaborative Adventure | Home | Character Collaborative Adventures | Josephus Collaborative Adventure

Armond Downtimes

Stories

Downtimes 09

While the group was investigating the injured survivor of the delegation Armond felt a pull to his idol. Armond sat down and started concentrating. Deep in his pocket he felt something get pulled out of him. Armond was falling. It was surreal, but looking around at his surroundings he was falling from himself. It was as if he was a miniature version of himself and he just fell from the height of his shoulder.

Maybe falling is the right word. He was being pulled. Like going down a mountain on a slide. Armond got jerked towards his belongs and saw that he was going to crash with his idol. Once Armond opened his eyes, he was laying on the floor of a cavern. It looked familiar, but he couldn't place it.

A child was standing over him looking down into Armonds face. The child was wearing a burlap sack and had a shaved head. "That was quite an entrance." the boy said while holding back a giggle. He offers a hand to bring Armond to his feet.

After Armond stands he asks "Where am I."

The boy replies "Where you were. This place has a name, but it isn't important and you don't want to know it. Let's call this place the in-between."

"Who are you." Armond asks.

The boy replies, "You know the answer to that question. For I called you and you and I are connected." The boy goes over to the small fire that lights the area and stokes it. "It has been a while since we have talked. Glad I finally got your attention. I tried to communicate with you when you were in the cave under Red Larch . Your friend has their magic. She can speak with the earth. I can feel what she does, but I can’t see it. I think you may be able to find a clue in her magic for your quest."

The boy starts drawing something in the ground with his scorched stick. "It is time I ask you for a favor. You are to kill your hostage. If he goes free he will alert the air cult you're on to them. He can't simply be killed. He needs to have his soul trapped."

"My friends are not going to like this." Armond says.

"They won't know you left the room. I will grant you access to Major Image and Invisibility. I will hold your Major Image once you leave the room." the boy says with a smile. The drawing is starting to look like a bird. "When you kill him, place the idol by his left foot. Energy leaves the body on the left side. I will capture him."

"You may deny this request, but I get two more before you can't deny me. The air genasi is going to die anyway." The boy tell you. "Do you accept this request?"

Downtimes 06 FB

Barikhol and Armond made it to a town during their travels. They were sitting at a tavern having a few drinks when Barikhol started quizzing Armond on what he has learned. Armond being a dedicated studient took all his questions seriously and made sure to think out all the answers before giving them. This task was getting a little harder after each drink.

While in the Tavern there was a bewer… berooer… Drink-maker! Who decided to join them. He talked about his booerie down the street and he invited Armond and Bear-ee-claw down to take a look. They agreed, but first… another drink!

They were being mean, but everyone was having a good time. They were testing Armonds ability to bew. This was tough, and Armond was not going to let them get the last laugh. So he tried to will up and focus to do well. It didn't help that Bary would tamper with the stuff that Armond was doing. For example: He cut the bag, he was throwing things , Armond thinks he remembers getting a wet willy. He was a jerk, but everyone was so drunk it was kind of funny.

The next morning. Barikhol and Armond came by to apologize to the brewer for making a mess and help him clean up. They worked together making another batch and give real instruction, vs drunken criticism to Armond . The brewers name was Poss and he had some interesting techniques. Barikhol and him shared some of their experiences and they all had a good laugh when Barikhol told the story of the Fire Mead. It has been long enough to where this story is now funny.

A week later they got to try the mead they made. The first one was Armonds Drunken Drink. It was actually pretty good. Armond thought he accidently stumbled onto something. Barikhol and Poss didn't think so.

Poss told Armond he would try to sell it, and if they ever pass back through this town again.

Training Brew Crafting (40/150) : Since your training form a PC it is between you and him if he wants compensation.

Downtime 05

Finnis

Growing up is never easy, but when you don’t know who your father was and being the son to a whore always makes it a little harder. In the pass Finnis's mother was a beautiful young woman that courted many men of high standards. One day, as she was escorting a wealth merchant to a gala to celebrate the trade agreement with the Eldanians (Elves), she caught the eye of Lord Ailmar Faeranduil, Royal Ambassador of Eldania. Lord Ailmar was infatuated with this human beauty. Later that evening Ailmar stole away Theresa (Finnis's mother), dancing and chatting the night away. While Ailmar was in Irieabor, the two spent every waking moment with each other. Theresa was in heaven, hoping finally she found the right man to take her away. One the eve of Ailmar departure, Ailmar confessed his undying love for Theresa and consummated their relationship that night. In the morning Ailmar had Theresa go gather her belongings from her home. When she return the palace guards halted her from entering the royal guest quarters. She pleaded with them to let her in, telling them to go get Lord Ailmar to explain who she was but the guards only informed her that Lord Ailmar had already left. Devastated, Theresa slunk back to her megger home. Weeks later she found she was with child. Now with a growing midsection none of her wealth clientele wanted anything to do with her. Without their money she had to move into the slums where conditions where inhuman at times. The only bit of hope was Father Yorgenson, a cleric in the service of Ilmater. He would bring her food and provisions and what little coin he could scrap together. It was Father Yorgenson that delivered Theresa child Finnis. When Theresa saw her child she immediately became scornful of him, for he bared the look of the elves. Father Yorgenson told her not to hate her child for he had done nothing to her; but merely been born. Over the next few years all Theresa could do to earn a living was to turn cheap tricks for change. In doing so had caught a devastating disease that ravaged her body. Father Yorgenson tried everything he could but Theresa surcomed to the disease leaving behind her four year old son Finnis.

Father Yorgenson had sent Finnis to go live at the orphanage but kept an eye out for him. Finnis had a hard time relating to the other kids because he was different; his ears where pointer, his eyes slanted more and the fact he could see in the dark. The kids would often call him names like mudblood or half breed to name a few. They would also bully him and take is food and rip his clothes. So Finnis would hide away from the other kids, stealing food from the kitchen after it closed. Finnis started sneaking away from the orphanage during the day. One day while away from the orphanage Finnis ran into a group of homeless kids. They ask where he was from because they haven't seen him around before. He explained that he was from the orphanage but hate being there because of the treatment he received for being different. The group of kids let him join them telling him that the difference between them is what makes them great. As Finnis took a closer look at these kids he noticed that most of them weren't human. There were half elves, a half orc, and even a tiefling. Finnis asked, how they ate and where did they sleep? They answer that they make do by stealing what they need and sleep here and there. They invite Finnis to abandon the orphanage and join their group. After think long about it he decide to do just that. Over the next few months Finnis picked up the art of stealing and learned all the nooks and crannies throughout the city. Many a days were spent picking the pockets of travelers stopping to watch the entertainment in the square. One particular day while enjoying his favorite pastime he notice a man watching him. Finnis tried to sneak away but every time he did the man would appear in front of him. Scared, he ran as fast as he could down the alleys twisting and turn but was caught. The man took him aside and informed him that he has come to the attention of the thieves’ guild. He explain that thieving without the permission would get you punished. The man told Finnis that the guild has offered him a provisionary membership and with it he and his friends could pilfer without fear of retaliation from the guild with the standard payment of 50% of the plunder. Thinking of his friend’s safety he accepted the invitation. Finnis was told to go down to the Mermaid's Armpit and talk to Jack. So off Finnis went, down to the docks to find this Jack.

Upon arriving at the Mermaid's Armpit, Finnis took note how seedy the place was. Finnis enter the bar and began scanning the crowd for this "Jack" fello. As his look around he got some glances from some patrons but then he noticed one individual was staring him down. He took this to be Jack. He headed over to where Jack was when he noticed a sharp sting in his side. As Finnis looked down he saw a man standing next to him with a dagger to Finnis side as the man said "always stay alert and know your surroundings". The man withdraw the blade and beckoned Finnis to join him in a private room. Once inside, the man introduced himself as Jack the Blade. Finnis asked about the other guy he thought was Jack. Jack laughs, "he was a teller; I had him stare at you as a distraction". Jack seeing the bewildered look on Finnis face began explaining the ins and outs of the guild structure; how a "teller" was not a member but was an informant under the "protection" of the guild, the eyes and ears of the guild. Jack explained that the guild was officially call The Artisan's guild to give legitimacy and that the ranks within are appropriately named Apprentice, Journeyman, and Master. He also explain the percentages owed to the guild of each rank. Finnis asked about non guild thieves, if they were "punished" for not having permission. Jack said that an independent contractor "could" work without being a member but has to pay for a temporary permit and pay 50% fee on everything pilfered. Jack went further and explain about the assassin's guild. Jack explained that there was an uneasy truce between the two guilds and if you see one of the Nightshadows, turn around and go about your business elsewhere. With that Jack got up telling Finnis "you are free to go but you will report back to me here once a week for the guilds cut of your pilfering, understood?" Finnis nodded in understanding and left.

Finnis meet up with his group and informed them of what transpired. They all were upset and refused to pay the guild anything; it was theirs, it was their way of surviving, and nobody was taking that from them. A week passed and Finnis didn’t show up to meet Jack. That night when the group meet back up, "Tiny" the half orc didn’t show up. They went out to looking for him only to find Jack waiting for them. "What do you want?" one of the half elves asked. "You see, I'm a little disappointed. I explained everything to you Finnis very clearly and you (glancing at Finnis) indicated that you understood but you missed our meeting. Now a lesson must be learned. "Tiny" will not be coming back!" At this, everyone in the group rush forward at Jack but was meet with Jack's lightning reflexes; stabbing several and knocking a few aside. They understood they were outmatched. "Now listen to me, you WILL comply or another will disappear! Then another, and another, until you comply or no one is left!" Jack said sternly as Jack backed into the shadows and disappeared. The group was left there in disbelief. What were they to do? Tiny was dead, and if they didn’t give half of their thieving another of their group would die; but they need all of it to survive. Finnis offered to join the guild as a full member and would pay for his friends so they wouldn’t have to pay. They knew that if Finnis did this then he couldn't be with them. He would belong to the guild and had to do what they wanted. Reluctantly they all agreed and said their farewells.

Over the course of a year, under Jack's tutelage, Finnis had become quite the thief. He was the highest pilfering apprentice in the guild. Many of the Journeyman took notice and Finnis had earn the moniker "The Hand" among them. This caused animosity between other apprentices and Finnis. Within the next six months Finnis attain the rank of Journeyman. Now Finnis could do jobs without Jack babysitting him. During one of Finnis jobs he decide to stop by to see his old friends that he hasn’t seen in over a year and a half. When he got to their old hideout no one was there. It looked like it had been broken into and hasn’t been used in a very long time. Worried, he went looking for some "tellers" in the area to find out any information about his friends. He did find one teller able to give him what he wanted. The teller informed him that the city guard raided their hideout, arresting any they captured. Some escaped and went into hiding, but as to where they are now she doesn’t know. Over a few weeks, Finnis was able to track down the tiefling Jandace. She was at the temple of Ilmater. When Finnis got to the temple he found that Father Yorgenson was still there. He was actually tending to Jandace. Jandace had become very sick. She had been living in the sewers and eating rotten food to survive. "Jandace is dying! She has an infection that I cannot heal. She doesn’t have much time left in this world. Go to her, comfort her in her last hours." Father Yorgenson says. Finnis ran to her room and went to her side. Finnis started cry and apologizing for leaving her and the others. As she opened her eyes she placed a hand on Finnis shoulder, she says "it is not your fault, you did the best you could do for us. We would have died long ago if it wasn’t for your aid. We were unfortunate that the guards found us and it had nothing to do with you. I am at peace. Father Yorgenson has been telling me of the tenants of Ilmater." Finnis asks about the others as Jandace's face took on a grim appearance. "The ones that were capture were either executed or sent to labor camps. The few that got away left the city or perished trying to survive." Finnis felt his heart drop. All of his friends; no, family, were gone. Finnis stayed with Jandace until the morning when she past. Father Yorgenson talk with Finnis; helping him cope with his losses. The Father explain that what Finnis did for them was what Ilmater teaches, suffering for others to easy the pains. That was exactly what Finnis did by joining the guild and sending them aid by paying their fees and sending them money. Finnis talk with the Father for a while about Ilmater. Finnis paid for Jandace's funeral.

Getting back to normalcy, Finnis started taking more perilous jobs. On one such job, robbing a moving carriage, he made a flub and spooked the horses cause the carriage to careening out of control through the city. Just as luck would have it, a disheveled person decide to walk across the street at the exact time the carriage came flying by. Finnis, seeing this, leaped up between the horses and launch out in front of them to tackle the dimwit crossing. As Finnis tackled the man, Finnis instinctively rolls along under the carriage trying to avoid any injuries. After the carriage continues on, Finnis manages to stand the guy up asking him "are you daft? That carriage would have killed you if I hadn't been there." He simply replied "that’s what I was hoping it would do." Finnis step back and took a good look at him. He had nothing on but rags with dried blood staining the back of his shirt. Quickly Finnis hurried the man off the street and into the alley way as to not draw attention to themselves. Finnis, using the back alleys, brought the man to Father Yorgenson to care for him. Before leaving Finnis asked the man his name. He replied " Armond ....my name is Armond , Armond Creed." With that Finnis left. Back at the guild hall Finnis had to answer for the botched heist. The Grand Master decide to take all of Finnis's take on the next few heist to repay what guild might of made from the carriage job. Finnis not happy with this decision but could only except it. That night Finnis brood over the thought that it was Armond 's fault that he has to repay the guild. If he had to repay the guild then Armond would have to repay Finnis. So the next morning, Finnis went to the temple of Ilmater seeking Armond . Once he found Armond , Finnis demeanor changed. As he look upon Armond , he could see that he had fresh burns on his left arm no more than a couple weeks old and had several fresh deep lacerations across his back. Father Yorgenson was applying an alchemical medicine to add in healing. Finnis decided to help Armond , he would make him his personal "teller". Once Armond was well enough Finnis pulled some strings and got Armond a job as a dockhand. Armond work the docks help unload cargo keeping an eye and ear on what was coming and going. The job last a month or so just long enough to score a heist or two of rare items be smuggled into the city. That was until Armond accidently got tangled up in some dock lines and fell in the harbor nearly drowning. So Finnis got Armond a job at the Mermaid's Armpit bussing tables. Armond again provided excellent intelligence on who and what was going down in the city. Again Armond had an accident, this time a bar fight broke out and he tried to stop it single handedly being stab several times. Luckily for him they were mere flesh wounds. Finnis, at wits end, ask Father Yorgenson if Armond could do odd jobs around the temple.

During this time, with Armond 's information, Finnis had become the highest ranking thief in the guild. Which in turn made Tibryn Blackmoor angry, for he was the highest. Even with his connections in the guard Tibryn couldn’t catch up Finnis. Every time Tibryn would get word of some jewels, coins or other items of valve whereabouts Finnis would steal them before Tibryn could even formula a plan. So Tibryn decided to get rid of his competition. Word spread that a wealthy merchant was coming to the city and he owned a rare gem worth a fortune. In the following week, such a merchant did arrive. He was surround by hired muscle almost constantly. The only time he wasn’t was when he slept. He was staying in a high end Inn that Finnis was familiar with. He had done several jobs there and had access to the crawl space in the roof. So Finnis formulated a plan to steal the gem. That night Finnis scaled the wall of the Inn and crawled through his secret access hatch. He made his way across the ceilings to the merchant's room. Quietly he remove a ceiling board and slow fished down his grab hook. Carefully and skillfully he managed to hook the merchant’s purse. Slowly he pulled it up and replace the board, making his way out the hatch. But once he stepped foot on the ground he was instantly swarms by guards. "How the hell?" went racing through his head. There was no way that they should of known he was there, let alone seen him. As the guard closed in Finnis launch up and over one of the guards tumbling as he went. As soon as his feet hit the ground he was gone; running down the alley ways trying to get away. To no avail at every turn there were guards. He tried climb up to the roofs to get away but was met with a sharp pain in his thigh. Looking down an arrow was protruding from his thigh with a rope attached. Suddenly Finnis felt a tug on his leg cause pain to shot through his body. As he hit the ground he was swarmed by guards. He felt manacles and leg irons being secured to his arms and legs. Once the guards finally back away, a Lieutenant stepped forward. "You thought you were cleaver. You thought we would never catch. You were wrong." Then the lieutenant started naming off all the crimes he was being charged with. As the charges were being list Finnis realized that most of those crimes weren't even jobs he pulled. Suddenly it hit him, those were jobs Tibryn pulled and how did the guard know about those. "That sneaky little snake, he framed me" Finnis mutter under his breath. Just at that moment the Lieutenant finished the list of charges and started laughing. As he reached into Finnis pouch he pulled out the merchant purse and opened it dropping a large piece of coal out. "You risked everything for this!" the Lieutenant said laughing. Finnis was hauled off to jail.

The following day Finnis was lead to the pillory. When he arrived the Lieutenant was there with a small bucket fill with some kind of fluid. Just before Finnis was out in the pillory the Lieutenant grab Finnis hands. As he plunged Finnins's hands into the bucket the Lieutenant snared "The Hand indeed". After a minute or two the Lieutenant remove Finnis's hands from the bucket. Finnis looked at them as red liquid dripped off; his hands were dyed red. With that he was leaded up the stair to the pillory to be put on display for the masses. As the citizens started to gather Finnis could he whispers among the crowd. Slowly the whisper started becoming louder until they turned into yells and screams. Next thing Finnis knew he was being pelted with rotten fruit or vegetables (depending on your definition of tomato). Wack! Blood streamed down Finnis forehead. "Must have been a rock" thought Finnis. This went on for a couple of hours until the crowd lost interest. An occasional snide remark or little kid throwing a tomato but nothing much for the rest of the day. But on the following day, the trumpeters trumpeted away with the town crier yelling throughout the street "today is a great day. The punishment of a thief is at hand. Ten lashes. Come all to see" Finnis was release from the pillory only to be marched into the square where a large wood stage had been erected. On this stage where several large posts with shackles hanging from the tops on either side. Finnis, along with several other prisoners, where lead up on to the stage and locked into the shackles dangling from the tops. Next a large monster of a man wearing a black hood came onto the stage. Again Finnis's crimes were read aloud along with the other criminals then the black hooded man began flogging one of the criminals with a cat-of-nine tail. The criminal cried out in pain, after the fourth hit passed out but the black hooded man continued until all ten lashes were administered. The crowd screamed out in cheer. The black hooded man stepped down the line, administering out the capital punishments. As Finnis waited his turn, he started noticing familiar faces among the crowd. For under hoods he could make out member of the thieves guild. Slowly they approached; moving through the crowd as a fish swims through water. Just as the administrator of punishment step behind Finnis; a load cry rang out followed by a spear striking the hooded man squarely in his back. As the hooded man staggered forward, he turned around just in time to see the other spear as it struck through his chest. Loud shouts, "Guards, Guards" echoed across the square. With that several hooded figures darted out from within the crowd clashing with what guard was there. Small groups of hooded figures raced across the square to block off the streets leading in. Finnis heard someone come up behind him then felt the shackles on his wrist fall loose. There he was standing in all his glory, Armond had come to the rescue. Armond quickly lead Finnis off the stage and into an alley way. They were meet by Jack who briefly explained, while moving through the alley ways, that the guild masters found out that Finnis was framed and where taking actions to correct the situation. Jack explained that because Finnis was now widely known in the city he could no longer be a member of the guild and he was to leave the city. Finally they reached the outer wall. As Finnis asked how they were going to escape the city a couple of ropes dangled down the wall. Jack grab on and said "you and Armond will climb over the wall. On the other side I have to men with horses and provisions. Take the road north to Asbravn. Once there go to Sambori's Sundries-in-trade, speak to Sambori and give him this, as jack hand Finnis a broken music box, tell him you would like to find a good home for it. He will set you up with a merchant caravan to Baldur's gate from there it's up you to do with your life. "Safe journey" as Jack clasps Finnis's forearm. Over the wall Finnis and Armond went; taking the horse they road north to Asbravn where Finnis and Armond departed with each other.

Rewards:
- Background Updates

Downtimes 04

{I apologies in advance, I got carried away with the story and couldn’t stop writing. Not all DTs will be this long.}

Armond , Barikhol , and Wyer would wake up around the same time every morning around sunrise. Armond would practice his polearm drills. He would remember the things his teachers would impart in him. Chin up, elbows in, balance low, and many other reminders Armond had, but still needed to practice more. So he did, every morning, alongside his friends.  Barikhol would practice his kata making self-corrections on procedure here and there. He would also practice balance exercises, which looked a little funny for a Dwarf, but Barikhol did them well. Wyer would pray. He had his morning meditation rituals and he would ask Tempus for his blessings for the day.  At the end of their morning rituals they would all spar and work up an appetite.

Sitting around the breakfast table they talked about what they plan on doing. Armond mentioned that he wants to find out more about the cult activities and there has to be something he can research on them. They couldn’t have appeared out of nowhere. Wyna the waitress tells Armond that he may have luck at Endrith ’s shop, Vallivoe’s Sundries . He collects a lot of things and may have something or know where to get it.

Once Armond finishes his meal he informs everyone he is off to do some research. Rowena tells Armond , “If you find a place to get books, see if you can find something on minor gods. I remembered something about the carvings on the knife.” Armond is also interested in finding out where his knife comes from. Armond visited his Patron again about the knife.

His Patron said “Oh, I have seen those carvings before. It has something to do with a dead religion. I honestly never paid close attention to it because they were never a problem and I couldn’t use them.” He told Armond the Knife isn’t magical, but it looks like something “mortals” would use to do rituals.

His patron didn’t mention anything about a minor god, but Rowena is a researcher so she may have seen something like this before. “If I saw a list of them, I may remember where those are from.” She says.

Armond agrees and heads out to Endrith , the rambling gnome. Endrith is not in his shop, Armond discovered this when he approached a locked door and a sign that read “Out Back”. Armond then heard a loud boom and felt the pulse of the explosion.

Armond got behind the workshop as fast as he could finding Endrith thrown back into a large pile of hay. Endrith was alive, but had a few minor injuries. “Maybe I am not giving enough space for the pressure I am creating.” Endrith says as Armond helps him out of the stack. “This is going to take me a week to repair this.”

Armond asks the obvious question, but is nervous because he know this isn’t going to be an easy answer: “What is this thing?”

Endrith , forgetting his wounds, “I introduce you to the Tremendous Aquatic Density Converter Cistern Mechanism!” Endrith stands there with an excited expression on his face. Armond is slightly confused and a little surprised that he is still in the same hour of asking the question.

“Ok? But what does it do?” Armond courageously asked as his follow-up question.

Endriths face fell, “Honestly? I have no idea. You see this design came to me in a dream. I wasn’t exactly sure what it does, but I knew if I built it I would find its use or it would find its use. Really, you never know with these things . My cousin, his name was Tindrink Donkoargo Finkvizz Draxledwadle Melrond and he invented the famous Melrond’s Foolproof Dishwasher. He had no idea what he was on to and was completely surprised when he figured out what it was that he created… Tindrink Donkoargo Finkvizz Draxledwadle Melrond wasn’t even an engineer, he was a biologist... He was studying this black pudding that he found while adventuring one day (he went on to tell the exact adventure of how he came across it)... Come to find out the pudding was actually a lifeform. It actually eats organic leftovers… After discovering what it ate he started breeding these little things to create the Melrond’s Foolproof Dishwasher (at this point he is now describing where his cousin is famous and where his dishwasher is used)… So sometimes you just need to experiment first and find your invention later.”

During that entire exchange Armond tried many times, unsuccessfully, to stop Endrith . Armond finally gave up and had a seat to wait on Endrith to finish. “I need help researching cults or cult activities.” Armond finally said to Endrith , “Do you have any books, information, or anything that would lead me in the right direction?”

Endrith looked up at Armond and said “I have been waiting for you to ask.” Armond obviously a little confused because this shouldn’t be a normal question people are asking. “There was a Bard in town, Bellamir , who asked me to give something to you, but to wait till you asked for it.” Armond notices Endrith look at his bracelet he wears on the left arm. It has a sketch of a moon and something else on it. Endrith covered it up with his sleeve. “We roll with the same people. Bellamir said you would want this.” Endrith goes digging through his workspace and pulls out a journal. “He said you will know when you’re ready for this. It should give you a good start on what you need to know.”

Endrith paused while Armond started flipping through the pages. It seemed to be a journal on someone studying the cult’s activity. The ink in the journal isn’t that old maybe 5 – 10 years. It is not a lot of information, but it is definitely more than Armond knows. “Without a past, no being can appreciate what they have, and where they may be going.” Armond looks up not familiar with the expression. Endrith answers his unasked question. “It’s something Bellamir would say.”

Armond asks “I may as well ask. Do you know where I can go to get some items I think may be magical identified? Also do you have a list, book, or something that names all the minor gods?”

“No I don’t have anything about the minor gods… or at least I don’t think I do.” He replies looking around at all his ‘junk’. “You may have better luck at the temple. But Kaylessa , of Swinging Sword , can actually identify magical items. I use her all the time when stuff comes into my shop.”

Armond kind of remembers his last encounter with Kaylessa . She seemed a little upset after talking with Armond . She should have communicated better what he needed to do. How was he to know that she would “trust” him? Actually, now that Armond is thinking about it, this is kind of her fault that she got hurt. The diplomatic part of Armond mind was telling him that he isn’t going to get anywhere with her if he goes in there with that argument. It was a misunderstanding.

On Endrith 's advice, Armond headed down to Swinging Sword to talk to Kaylessa about identifying the few magic items. The whole way there Armond just kept playing the scenarios over and over again in his head, knowing that his last encounter was not the best, trying to find the best outcome. Stopping outside the door, Armond took one final breath and open the door stepping through. As Armond enter Swinging Sword he could see Kaylessa look up from the bar. As he approached, Kaylessa started around the end of the bar coming to meet him halfway. Just as Kaylessa was about to talk Armond put up his hand "is there somewhere we could talk privately?" Kaylessa a little taken back, motioned to Armond to follow. Kaylessa went to her office in the back and closed the door behind Armond . As she turned around and about to speak again, Armond put his hand up to silence her. Now visibly irritated, Armond spoke quickly. "I am sorry about earlier. I forgot that you and your patrons are not use to seeing that kind of thing. I should have come to you without the body and after I cleaned up a bit." At this Kaylessa calmed down some. "I am from a militant background and was expected to provide proof of completion. Again I am sorry."

After Armond finished speaking, and Kaylessa sensing some alternative motive ask "was ‘dis tee only reason you come heere?" as Kaylessa looked down at Armond 's hand. In Armond 's hand down at his side, he held about an eighteen inch long object wrapped in a cloth.

"It wasn't but that need to be said, I didn’t think about how you would feel seeing the body. I am truly sorry." As Armond brought up the object, he unwrapped it revealing what appears to be a wand of some kind. It has a blue crystalline flame atop a gold or brass shaft with ring around the shaft segmenting it. "I heard from Endrith that you can identify magical properties of an item" Armond asked half questioning half stating.

"Indeed, but t’ere is a price." Before Armond could respond, she add "I don’t need your coin, but I do have a favah to ask."

Armond thought about it for a second, "OK, but I need another item identified along with the wand" Kaylessa nodded in understanding. Armond took off his pack and removed a four to six inch glass sphere with arcane ruins carve around it. "I will leave them with you for a while so you can identify them, and when I come back you can ask your favor." With that Armond laid the items on her desk and began to leave.

As he open her office door she said "remember I don’t need bodies for proof, I trust you to do good." With a smile Armond left to let Kayessa get to her work.

As Armond walked out the door a man in the hall way looks up at him and says "Sorry, I didn’t want to disturb you and the miss. I am sure she appreciates the apology, she really is glad you all are here." The man holds himself like he is the help. Armond remembers the days when he used to hold himself similarly. The man is human, with only one eye. He smells a very familiar smell that Armond remembers from his stable days.

Armond asks, "Who are you?"

Kayessa opens the door, "Iraun? Everyting' all right?"

Iraun looks over at her with his one eye and gets a huge grin. "Yes mam. I was hoping to have a word." he looks back at Armond , "I am the stable master for Ms Kaylessa . If you have an animal that needs attention. I will take good care of ‘em." He steps into her office.

Armond was just about to head up to his room to start looking into his book when he remembered the list of gods. Armond went over to the Allfaiths Shrine and spoke with Imdarr . He explained how they were looking into carvings left by a necromancer and Rowena thinks it may be related to a minor god. Imdarr said his services would cost Armond a gold, but he will be able to write out a list of minor gods and a brief description of what they've done. It will take him a couple days to gather up all the research.

For the next few days Armond uses the desk in his room to review the Journal he received from Endrith . The Journal was written in Dwarvin, but the author was referred himself as an elf. He never said his name, but he would say things like “my Elvin ears could hear…” Armond didn’t have much trouble reading the journal because one he could read Dwarvin, but two the author was writing this like he was reporting to someone. So his notes were not created for just his understanding.

The Elf ran across all four elemental cults (as he called them), but seemed to run into the Earth Cults or The Cult of the Black Earth most often.

Each of the 4 cults has a symbol like they ones Armond and the rest of the group already pieced together. The remaining cults are called:

Cult of the Crushing Wave
Cult of the Eternal Flame
Cult of the Howling Hatred

The earth Cults worships the implacable strength and unyielding resistance of the elemental earth. Cultist seek the power to destroy the works of civilization with landslides, sinkholes, or mighty earthquakes. This is how they demonstrate the true power of the elemental earth, and the futility of resistance.

The The Earth Cult can push its influence on the lands it lives in. They control animals and monsters that live or burrow in the ground. Creatures such as ankhegs or bulettes will even submit to the will of the Black Earth.

The Earth Cults are slow to act. They are willing to wait for the opportune moment to destroy their enemies.

The Author speaks of their leader, but has never seen him. His name is Marlos Urnrayle, the author knows that he wields a magical weapon named Ironfang . Many of his enemies have been brought before him and never seen again.

The The Earth Cult is highly suspicious of the Cult of Howling Hatred. They believe they are mercurial, unreliable, and out of touch with reality.

He doesn’t has nearly as much to say about the other cults. He talks about the destruction that was left behind from some of these cults, water with water, air with weather, fire with flame… but he didn’t seem to get to study them like he did the The Earth Cult . Most of the places attacked are in the North, but there are records of attacks all over the Sword Coast .

Armond would continue practice his forms every day. He would spar with Barikhol and Rowena . If Wyer was in town Wyer would join them. Even the new guy Ty would practice with them too.

One day in the Tavern Rowena started glowing a bright light that hurt the eyes to look at her. She realized that she found the god.

Rowena read from the parchment: "Velsharoon (pronounced VEL-shah-roon), the Archmage of Necromancy, was a vain, selfish, petty, but very canny deity consumed with vengeance, obsessed with experimenting on living and dead beings, and unconcerned with the fates of lesser creatures. In many ways he continued to act like the mortal he originally was, albeit with far greater power at his disposal than before."

“His followers used to pass messages by removing parts of the script from the top and bottom.” Rowena etches the script on a piece of paper and makes some markings at the top and bottom and continues, “It would be written in Draconic, but with a little catch.” She wipes off the blade and places below the writings on the paper and angles it till it gets just right. “It would be written upside down and backwards. You see with the missing pieces of wording and flipped, draconic could actually appear as a completely new language.” She looks down at the word “Combine”, well it was a draconic word that could roughly translate to combine, but that is what it means. Well now we know what it means, I guess we need to figure out what it did.

"We?" Armond mused. "You sure you want to continue this adventure with us? It is going to be pretty dangerous. We are going to hunt down villains like Bastian and the other cults. I am pretty sure looking into necromancy will get us into all sorts of trouble. I'm game, you?" The rest of the group looks to Rowena …

Armond knew Rowena was questioning if she wanted to stay with the new party or find her place elsewhere in the world. She has been kind of a nice change to have around.

That night when Armond returned to Swinging Sword Kaylessa bacon him to join her in her office. On the way she grabs one of the cleaning ladies and request she fetch Brother Eardon and send him to the office. “I have tee items ready for you.” And she pulls out the Wand and Orb. She explains the Wand is a Wand of Magic Missiles and the Orb is a DriftGlobe. She gives Armond a parchment that explains how they work.

A knock on the door signals Kaylessa “So for your payment, a frien’ of mine needs help.” She opens the door, “Dis is Brother Eardon , he is concerned about aboot sum Dwarven friends of his.”

Brother Eardon says, “It is most concerning. I was recently in Beliard by way of Westbridge and I know the delegation from Mirabar was planning to leave Beliard soon. This was about 2 tendays ago. They should have come through Red Larch by now. Kaylessa said you would probably look into this?”

For the rest of the week Armond tried to relax and take it easy because he knew the roads ahead were going to be tough. There was cult activity and they are powerful. Armond has read about some of their destructive force and knows that he and his friends are not ready to take on that power yet. But they can’t also allow this power to continue unchallenged.

Researching (2 days): Having the Wand and Glass Orb ID

Identified.

Recuperating (3 Days): Relaxing

For the next 24 hours at start of game player will gain advantage on saving throws.

Researching (5 days): Trying to find info on Cult activity in the surrounding lands. Possible villages that were attacked. Where people were possibly kidnapped.

Book on The Earth Cult
Gave leader of Cults name and weapon
Gave names of all 4 cults
Lead on Cult activities.

Imdar charges 1 gp for minor god list.

Downtime FB 02

Armond and Barikhol still had a long travel ahead of them to meet with Josephus and Wyer . They took their time with their travels, since there was nothing time pressing and one of the reasons to become an adventurer is to see the world.

Eventually the two came across a farm. It has been a long day’s journey and they may not have sun for much longer. The heroes were starting to notice that more and more frightening creatures were coming out at night the further they traveled. Not that the two didn't run into troubles along the way with goblins, kobolds, and a few random undead creatures. It was just noticeably more dangerous to be out at night the closer they got to waterdeep and the north.

When the two approached the farm they noticed the farmer, a half elf by the name of Lorfeanor. Lorfeanor is pleasant in appearance, with cropped white hair and soft gray eyes. He wears travel-stained clothing and several pouches hang from his belt. Lorfeanor was out cleaning up from a day's work. Barikhol offered the half-elf to share a bottle of wine that he made.  You three got to talking and Lorfeanor mentioned that his barn is actually a 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery . He said "My father is a legend in making beer. Almost every pub in the sword cost keeps at least a keg stocked of 'Pure Hoppiness'. I still make it and distribute it." he then asks, "Do you happen to know much about the machinery used to make beer? You see something seems to be wrong with by brew kettle and I was never good at fixing these things . My father built this along with an expert metal worker. He would have known exactly what to do."

After a little bit of evaluation Barikhol tells the Lorfeanor that Armond and himself can fix this. Barikhol explains that Armond is his apprentice and this is actually good training to learn how this process works. This equipment requires a lot of maintaining and it appears that the half elf has not been keeping up on this regularly. The solution, or at least where they should start, is that they need to breakdown and clean out all the equipment. From there they should notice exactly what is wrong.

Lorfeanor says "How about I give you a room and fine cooked meals every morning and night. I will even help you with this and pay for any supplies." Barikhol and Armond , knowing this is good training, agree to this and they get to work the next morning.

Barikhol would stop and explain things to Armond and Lorfeanor. It was kind of like a class and Barikhol was the instructor. Barikhol would comment how this setup was a work of art. Barikhol has seen many breweries in his travels, but never a machine as finely fashioned as this. This is probably why it didn't require as much maintenance and the machine held out this long before it desperately needed service.

About three days into working on the 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery , they realized they will need supplies. The Half Elf invited Barikhol and Armond to travel to town with him to make sure he is getting the right materials. About five miles out of town the three travelers saw a struggle. It appeared like someone was getting robbed and that the robber was using some kind of magic. Barikhol and Armond looked at each other and silently exchanged acceptance that they should do something.

The heroes jumped off their transport and made their way by placing the victim wagon between the robber and them. This way they have a better chance at getting close before being seen. Lorfeanor stayed back and out of the way. He is no fighter and would probably get in the way, more than aid the two heroes. Once the heroes got closer they could hear they robber. "A toll is due from any man that crosses this path. Failure to pay the told is an act of treason against the mud army. You sir tried to run, you tried to trick, you tried to steal from my lord Miraj Vizann (see Downtime 01). Now all your equipment and your life are forfeit. Do you have any last words?"

"Maybe, but you will never hear them." Barikhol said while looking over at Armond for approval of a good entrance liner. Armond quickly fist bumps Barikhol (Alright you two can change this piece if you want to, I am just imagining two 'not quite level 01s' and how they are still finding themselves). Armond takes aim at the sorcerer and lets his arrow fly true while Barikhol goes running and sliding for the mud slingers legs.

The mud slinger manages to form a shield with the dirt around him to barley block the arrow, but not quick enough to feel a pop in his knee and a sharp paid down his leg. The Mud slinger spins around to face Barikhol and forms arrows from the earth. This reminds Barikhol of his training with Master Oboku where many small stones would be launched at the dwarf and he had to anticipate where they would land so he could move just enough out of the way. This was not Barikhols favorite practice, but it came in handy now and he was able to roll, twist, grunt loudly, and turn just barely out of the way. A few cuts and scrapes is a much better outcome than what it could have been.

Another Arrow flies from Armonds bow and strikes through the mud slingers stomach. He pukes dirt and arches his back from the impact. Barikhol ceasing the moment grabs the arrow and pulls it through, spins around, and jams the tip in the sorcerer’s neck. The mud slinger looks surprised, like how one would look if they flipped a coin and it landed on its side. He was in shock and he was in pain. He collapsed to his knees and through a gurgled breath said, "Lord Vizann… (breaths in) will have… (wheezes) your heads." The mud magician collapsed forward and died. Sand blew off towards the north east into the sky as the last breath left his lungs.

The victim, a gnome, was super thankful and spoke super-fast. "You fellas just saved my life. I don't think I could ever repay you for your good dead. I was traveling from town back to my home when my wheel got trapped in the mud, and I thought… 'that is funny it hasn't rained in days here. Why is there mud?' I jumped off the wagon and the ground harden around my wheel. My wife would never believe me. You see it is our anniversary and I almost forgot. I promised to make her a meal, her favorite, lasagna. I was in my tool house, I own a company in the city. Wizzels, Wrapits, and More! I basically fix machinery of all types from all around the world. I am pretty skilled. It is almost like the thing-a-bobs just talk to me. Any way in lab…"

This would have continued forever if Barikhols didn't interrupt him with "Why don't you let us help you get your wagon un-stuck so you can get home to your wife, I am sure she is wondering where you're at." the heroes, and by this time Lorfeanor, suffered through constant one sided conversation as they got the wagon out of the ground and the gnome started driving off.

In the distance they could still hear the gnome talking to them "My mother always had a phrase for everything, 'if it ain't broke just wait till your father gets a hold of it.' my father, great man, was a tool designer. He had a pocket knife that did everything. Really! Actually you know what I think I have it in my wagon, let me look here… " you can see through the hole in the back of the wagon, now a couple hundred feet down the road the gnome riffling through all his stuff.

You three traveled on into town and got the supplies you needed and was able to make it back to the farm before dark. The rest of the week and a few days were spent working, training, and talking about one of Barikhols favorite subject, alcohol. After the project was done and Barikhol and Armond took a day of rest, the two heroes set off on more adventures.

[ Armond : add 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery (+10) to your character sheet.]

Downtime FB 01

While Barikhol and Armond were on their journey back to Josephus camp, they started discussing Barikhol 's profession. Armond , who was genuinely interested, kept pushing Barikhol for more. Barikhol decided to teach Armond the fine techniques on how this is done.

Armond requested not the start with the fire mead since that didn't work out so well last time. They came to a town and found a shop. Barikhol meet with the owner Rophingelm, a male elf. Rophingelm had a narrow face, with copper hair and brown eyes. He was dressed in worn clothing and wore a bronze amulet. Barikhol explained to him that he is skilled in brewing ale and would like to teach his new apprentice Armond . Rophingelm said that they couldn't have come at a better time and that he and his wife has a wedding to attend in Waterdeep and his boy, Finethilb, could man the shop if they would put their skills to use. He would also compensate them if the ale sells well minus the supplies used for teaching that will have to go to waste. There was also a room upstairs that the two could stay in.

Armond and Barikhol agreed to these term and begun crafting. The two helped man the shop for 3 tendays while Rophingelm and his wife traveled. They were not able to do much during many of the days while the ale was fermenting, but they helped Finethilb out where needed.

Once the Elf and his wife returned they looked like they have seen better times. Rophingelm said that outside of town they were mugged and robbed. They were carrying precious cargo with them, a gift from his brother for coming to the wedding.

Once questioned he told Armond and Barikhol what he knew. He said "The man called himself Miraj Vizann the great mud sorcerer. His skin was black and rough his eyes were like a light red stone. I don't know why they left me and my wife alive, but we waited for death as they took our stuff."

Rophingelm was sorry to have bothered Armond and Barikhol with this information, but was glad they took care of the shop and took care of their son. Rophingelm thanked for helping out around the shop and gave them a few coin (may have forced it if Armond and Barikhol rejected) for the trouble which Armond and Barikhol used to treat themselves to a feast.

[feel free to name the town this was in. If you wish to add any further details, please let me know first.

Armond : add 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery (15) to your character sheet.]

Prev | Home | Character Downtimes | Josephus Downtimes

Josephus Downtimes

Stories

Downtimes FB 06

Josephus was hammering the sign "The Tip Toe Hearts" down into the ground. "Another stage another gold piece" Josephus thought to himself. Josephus got pretty comfortable traveling with this performance group. They were kind to him, they paid well, and Josephus got to travel.

They were in the town of Loudwater. Josephus was looking around to see what he could do in the town. It was a nice little town, peaceful, clean, and the townsfolk seemed to always know everyone business. It wasn't by any means a small town, but is was smaller than most towns the group performs in. It was fun to listen to some people gossip when it wasn't cruel. Apparently, there was a girl in town who had ears of a fox. Not really sure what they meant Josephus just laughed it off and continued to the middle of town. When he got there Josephus saw there was an event going on, a fish cook-off.

Josephus wanted to get in on this action. After looking over the rules and instructions, Josephus went back to the group, borrowed a fishing pole (but all they had was a spear), and went off to get his catch.

Josephus had a nice catch and he went back to get to work on his meal. He caught a Lionfish and decided to do a Roasted Spear-Caught Lionfish. He went to the local market and picked up some fresh Island Clams to go with it. The rules said you just had to catch the fish, use what you got. Josephus put a lot of effort into this meal.

While making it, Josephus found himself in a daze. He caught himself remembering a time spent with Leaf and Talin down by a river fishing and hanging out together with their feet dangling in the water. It was good times. It is funny how things happen. You think of someone and they appear. Josephus would commonly wish this was true with Leaf. He wasn't even sure if Leaf was still alive. Josephus spun around to grab some supplies and saw a note in his bag.

It was small writing, but Josephus could read it. It was in Orcish, but the handwriting was slightly elvish:

I'm alive

It wasn't me

I wish I could have been fishing with you too

Destroy this note

There is only one person this note could be from, but why did he leave Josephus a note? Why didn't he come talk to Josephus ?

There were three chefs, the one in the middle was a large man, who didn't say a word the entire time. He would take a bite, make a note, and nod. Josephus saw his name card "Fishal".

The voting happened and Josephus won. When Josephus was called up to the stage he was shaking the mayors hand and getting congratulations from everyone when Josephus felt a sharp pain in his stomach. "Did I eat something bad?" The crowd must have noticed too, because there were gasp of shock. Josephus looked down and saw he had a crossbow bolt hanging out of him. "How did that get there?"

Looking out into the crowd Josephus saw a man in a cloak pull his hood a little tighter and disappear into the crowd.

Two days later Josephus woke up in the temple. A nurse saw him stir, "Careful now, you don't want to aggravate your wounds." she helped him sit up. "You're going to want to take it easy for a couple days, the healer said nothing serious got punctured so you should recover quickly. You're quite luck… sorry. I guess from your point of view getting hit with a bolt isn't lucky."

After Josephus recovered he talked with The Tip Toe Hearts and collected his winnings. He was going to take some time off to hunt down who tried to kill him.

Practice Profession (15 days) : FBDT characters earn just the tip from the gold earned. Josephus earnings was 15 and the tip was 2.7gp. This will be added to your bank.

Downtime 05

Josephus was helping a group called the Tip Toe Hearts set up stage. They paid him well traveling with them, and Josephus had further to go. He didn't mind waiting around in a new town for a couple days for the group to put on their show. The group was trust worthy and good company. Josephus needed good company. During his quiet moments Josephus can still see his men choking and dying from the nightshade. So Josephus tries not to have too many quiet times.

The work was more difficult today because it was raining. This shit is hard enough to setup in perfect outdoors conditions, but add in being wet, stepping in mud, and shivering from the cold and you are going to have a difficult day.

It was worth it. That night was clear skies as the gods shined the stars and the moon down on them. Their performance was spectacular, as always. After the show the streets were full of patrons heading back to their homes or off to a tavern for a few more.

The next morning Josephus woke to see some members of the troop a little distraught. After asking them what is worrying them, they told him about the attack last night.

Josephus made his way to town and to the room where it happened. The local sheriff looked at him and one of the troop leaders told the sheriff, "You can trust him. Josephus helps protect us." The sheriff and the troop leader must know each other, because the sheriff didn't hesitate in letting Josephus in on what happened.

The sheriff briefs Josephus , "I have heard rumors of this kind of attack. The downstairs neighbor told me that she heard someone playing what sounds like the pipes. There wasn't any other noise, but somehow the attacker tied a woman to the bed, and cut her open. If this doesn't give you the creeps, let me… are you ok around dead bodies?" The sheriff asks. After a nod of assurance from Josephus he continues, "The victims face is not as expected.”

He shows Josephus the woman. She was tied to the bed, naked, bloodied from being cut open, but her face was surprising. She had the look of pure pleasure. Like everything was perfect. This is more nerve racking then any death Josephus has ever seen.

In the room was a doctor inspecting the body. He tells the sheriff, "She is missing some bones. They were removed. The way her body looks, this was done with finesses."

The sheriff tells Josephus , "The killer is being call Windharrow. The only thing people have put together of him is that someone hears music coming from a pipe flute the night before the body is found. Take care of this troupe. They are my friends."

After Josephus left he reached into his pocket and pulled out the note he accidently lifted from one of his friends. "By orders of General Zanther, I hereby command a soldier from {Still need Army Name} to execute Harald Grayspear aka Windharrow. Windharrow is a known cult member of the Cult of Howling Hatred and has been seen in the presence of Aerisi Kalinoth. This mission needs to be done under stealth."

They traveled on and the troupe once again paid Josephus for traveling with them.

Rewards:

1.6gp. Total earned that week was 11.6gp, but this is a flashback downtime and the only thing kept is the Tip. Gold is available for character

Downtime 04

Josephus wakes up the next morning and decides he is going to need some additional coin. He thinks it is about time he perfect Crumblecake.

Crumblecakes are moist loaves from nuts, chickpea mash, chopped roots and greens, turkey and wildfowl scraps, all baked together.

They are bland at best, but they are nourishing. The original maker was actually on to something. One loaf could work as your rations for a very long trip. It gives you what you need to survive, but it doesn’t fulfill that pleasure sense of good food.

Josephus stops into Mangobarl Lorren Bakery. His daughter is working behind the counter today with her father. Juli-anne meet the characters on their first trip into Red Larch . She greets Josephus when he comes in.

"if it isn't Mr Crumblecake!" she says with a smile. "Come to take another crack?" Her father chuckles a little.

"Really it is a bland food, I don't think it can be made better. Why don't we cook something else?" he says knowing Josephus is the stubborn type.

Josephus tells Magobarl, "We are on to something. Nothing will last as long as a loaf of crumblecake, you have many visitors in the town and they are all on long travels. It is called the long road for a reason. If we can make Crumblecake at least palatable, people will want it, because it will last."

Juli-anne tells Josephus , "ok… what can we do?"

They go to work and start messing with many different things they have locally in the north. Juli-anne and Josephus go to the market together. While they are finishing up they meet Grund .

Grund is a half or pickle vendor.  “Orc Fingers! Get your Orc Fingers! I got em fresh for ye!” Josephus noticed kids would try and sneak off with some from the cart. Most of the time they were caught by Grund , but a couple times they would succeed. Grund would see them once it is too late and he would shake his fist at them and say “I gonna tell ye mum.” Then he would chuckle. Josephus noticed it was a game. If the children were caught they would pay up, but if they succeeded they won a pickle, err Orc Finger, for free.

"Oh Grund you're never going to make a profit with this kids liberating your supplies." Juli-anne says to him.

"It OK. I know der mum and dads. They throw me a coin or two to make up for their boys a playing. They don't mean no harm." Grund says. "Would you like an orc finger?"

"You know it is kind of morbid you call them that, being…" Juli-anne started.

"What?" Grund said "Being what?"

"well…" she replied "being half orc."

"I am not. You take that back." Grund says with a smile. "You know I am more like two halfs orc. Which makes me closer to the human side."

Josephus not being a math expert still feels this isn't right. "Whatever you say." Juli-anne says as she nudges Josephus to start moving along.

As they start walking Josephus feels Juli-anne reach for his hand. He looks down and sees that she is placing a pickle in his palm. She looks at Josephus scandalously and takes a bite and turns around to tell Grund buy. "Have a good day Grund ." she says with a mouthful of pickle.

"What the? How did… Juli-anne I know where you work!" he says laughing.

She pats her side "Check your pockets!" Grund does and he pulls out a few coins. "You stay sharp and maybe you will catch me next time."

They get back to the shop and start baking. This went on for a few days when finally they hit it. They make a batch that actually has some taste. It is by no means great, but it isn't terrible. The selling point is it will last longer than any loaf of bread.

Mangobarl Lorren taste it and tells Josephus that he thinks he can sell this.

A couple days later Josephus come back into the shop to see how it did. Mangobarl Lorren pulls out some coins and says, "Here is your share. Thank you for the help."

Practice Profession 10: earn 10 gp

Downtime FB 02

During some point while Armond is adventuring off to find Barikhol , Josephus decides to adventure off to try and earn some coin. Josephus is a grand cook, from the first time he lad his hands on a wooden spoon he knew that it was only natural. At some point in his life he realized that being in a kitchen wasn’t enough and this lead him on to become an adventurer.

Josephus told Wyer that he was going to head to Waterdeep for a couple weeks and he is welcome to join him if he wants to. Wyer , having nothing better to do and wanting to find a temple to pray at, decided to join him. The journey took a couple of days and along the way they stayed at a couple inns. Josephus and Wyer noticed that the roads were much more dangerous these days than they have been.

Once Josephus arrived in WaterDeep he set off looking for employment. It took a few restaurants that turned him down before he found ‘The Codfather’. There was a sign that read, “need cook with skills”. A man on the inside explained that their normal, world renowned, cook has had an unexpected death in the family and had to travel. The owner, Mr Fishal, will meet Josephus in the kitchen.

Josephus doesn’t normally get to work with seafood and took this as a unique challenge. Before getting started he walked the kitchen familiarizing himself with everything. The owner watched him quizzically while Josephus would do things like tap on a pan or test the flames from the grill.  Josephus pulled out many different samples of foods and would take a small taste of a few he was unfamiliar with. After about 10 minutes of this Josephus said “I am ready.”

He got started gathering, mixing, preheating, seasoning, and arranging. By this time a few other kitchen staff stood around to watch him work. A waiter saw what was happening and went to get a table and chair for the owner. A few staff members started taking notes and asking questions, trying to keep them brief to not disturb this new cook. Finally, Josephus finished his dish and started to bring it to the table, when a staff member stepped in front of him stopping his progress.

It was a young girl around the age of 19. She takes the tongs out of Josephus hands, moves somethings around on the plate, grabs a flower, and places it on the plate. Josephus had a tough time looking away from this girl. She had the most beautiful face that he has seen in a very long time. When he finally looked in the almost awkward moment of silence Josephus could see that by adding this garnish and rearranging the food she drastically improved the appearance of his dish. Seeing the look on Josephus face of understanding the girl smiled and kindly moved out of the way.

Josephus placed the plate in front of the owner and he stared at it for a very long time. He sniffed it, spun it, stood up and walked around the table to see it from other angles. Josephus has never had his food appraised so precisely in his life, and never this much before someone actually taking a bite. The worst part is the owner never said a word. Not one word from the moment they stepped into the kitchen.

Josephus about to say something to break the silence was nudged by the cute girl. Taking a look at her and the girl not looking back at him he could see the most imperceptible shake of the head. The owner took his first bite, stood up, and walked out of the kitchen. Josephus truly thinking he has screwed up. He said nothing. Not one thing. This was the rudest he has experience that he can remember. He could have at least told him what it is that he wanted. At this moment everyone started to clap.

Josephus obviously confused looks around trying to make sense of all this. “He didn’t tell you to get out. That means you got the job. My name is Joane, we should get started preparing what is for dinner.” Joane is exceptionally beautiful, with brown hair and dark amber eyes. She is wearing her kitchen uniform, but has a neckless with a cog shaped locket that dangles on her chess. Joane speaks with a timid voice, but walks with confidence.

One night during dinner Josephus was cleaning up and saw a tab for a familiar name. A man by the name of “Harald Grayspear” apparently had eaten here (See Downtime 01). After Josephus shift he tried to see if he could find out more information on Grayspear, but he apparently already left town. The rest of the week, Josephus couldn’t prove it, but he felt like someone was watching him.

The rest of the week working in the kitchen was amazing, but all good things come to an end. The previous cook returned and was very gracious for Josephus taking over the kitchen. They told Josephus anytime he is back in Waterdeep to come by. Joane gave Josephus her contact information, and said to look her up when he is back in town.

[Rick what happened with you and Joane is completely up to you.]

[ Josephus was paid for the week, but since this is FBDT the money gain has been spent except for any overage of 1gp found buried in your coin purse]

Downtime FB 01

Josephus was venturing along the terrain when he stumbled across a camp of people. They kindly invited him to join their gathering. Josephus told them he was looking for work and they explained that he is in luck. They are traveling and are in need a person who can cook. They have been surviving off of rations for about 10 days and they do not wish to continue eating this crap.

Josephus took this job and ventured to [enter location] with them. They were a kind group, a theatre group. They were traveling to do a play. Josephus got to watch and enjoy their performances of this princess that was put through test before she could marry the queens son. It was a sort of comedy.

One night while preparing a meal, Josephus found in his bag a note that didn't belong to him. He must have gathered it up from the camp where his companions… well he doesn't want to think about that. It must have been one of theirs. Curiosity got the best of Josephus and he read it.

It was one of his friends. They had a mission that they were to arrest a male half elf that goes by the name of Windharrow. His true name is Harald Grayspear. He is a minstrel and is in the services of a person by the name of Aerisi Kalinoth.

Josephus arrived safely in [enter location] with the group. They said if you ever are in a location where the Tip Toe Hearts are performing. Come find us and we will get you awesome seats. They gave Josephus some coin and wished him well.

[add 1 gp 95 silver to your overall inventory]

Armond Downtimes | Home | Character Downtimes | Barikhol Downtimes

Tyelknowle Downtimes

Stories

Downtimes FB 06

The church of Tymora had many ways of earning blessings (normally in the form of coins). They have ties with the Harpers faction, as many Harpers give blessings to Lady Luck. The Harpers served the church well over the years and the church would normally return their blessings with gifts of magical items.

The Church would also sell some magical items such as potions, scrolls, and glowstones. This helped bring a portion of income into Tymora's organization.

Tyelknowle would sometimes have duty helping make potions and glowstones. Clerics often would be given this task since they understood how the spells, that went into making these components, worked. Scrolls were normally given to more seasoned clerics, as there could be dangerous effects from failing to properly making a scroll.

The Church of Tymora has a ritual where they send their clerics out on a holy mission. They are to spread the word and do good things for others and The Lady Who Smiles may return their kindness.

Jurras Bigglesworth was holding a sack and the clerics who chose to go on this holy mission were lined up. Each one would reach into this back and pull out a stone. Written on the stone was a message and the Cleric was to interpret it and head on their journey. Many times the stone had 1 or 2 words and a direction. The Clerics didn't know where they were going till they got there.

The message was in Elvin. It read "Family" and the stone was marked to the south. Ty packed his things and started heading south. He visited many places and meet many people, but nothing felt right. Jurras said "You will know when you find it."

Ty would know. He arrived in a small village and the whole village seemed dismayed, but trying to get anyone to talk was difficult. Ty finally cornered a local and convinced him to spill what is going on.

"if anyone knew I was talking to a foreigner, I would be hung." the baker said to Ty. "The town has been invaded by mud men. They are forcing many of us to work for their temple. If we speak they hang the person who spoke and 3 of the taken. Please, just go. I don't want anyone hurt."

Ty let the man go as he didn't want to endanger him any further. Ty knew this was his mission. These Families were in trouble, and he knew he could help. Ty used his talents of being a rogue to observe and find what he could do. Ty knew it was just a few days ride to Baldurs gate from here and there were some Harper contacts he could get some help from.

Ty left town and found a rider to deliver a message. Ty knew the right words to say so very few people would understand. Rogues have a language all of their own and it has been a while since Ty has had to use Thieves Cant, but he remembers it well. He knew a contact in town that would be able to get the right people. Hopefully, they will be able to get the message to the right people in time.

Ty watched town for a few more days till he saw some thugs come into town. He hated not acting, but Ty knew the bigger picture was to find where they are keeping the slaves. He followed the slavers back to their base of operations. As Ty was leaving to go back to leave a message for the Harpers (well hopefully) Ty was surprised by running into another guy.

Anger flooded both of their faces. These two had history. Across from Ty was a man by the name of Expo . He caused a lot of problems for Ty and his clan back in the day. Expo and Joclyn fell in love and Joclyn joined Expo gang of highwaymen.

Expo said in a whisper, "What are you doing here? I thought you left the Mud-Bloods ."

Ty replied, "I did, what are you doing here?"

Expo : " Joclyn , isn't that why you're here?"

Ty: " Joclyn ? She is here?"

Expo said in a low tone, "Don't play with me."

Ty shushed him and nodded for Expo to follow. After they got a good distance Ty spoke, "I am looking into the rumor of slavers. I had no idea that Joclyn was here."

Expo looking like he is not really believing Ty said, "Come on, you're here coincidently?"

Ty responded, "I am here by the luck of Tymora."

Expo rolled his eyes, but couldn't deny he needed help.

Tyelknowle filled Expo in on the plan. They went back to the location where Ty was to meet with the Harpers. They were not there. Ty left a marker with a message to let the Harpers know where the camp was.

Expo told Ty, "I have men. We can take them."

Ty: "I am not interested in working with criminals."

Expo : "Don't you follow a god of coincidence? People are in trouble and you need more than just yourself to save them. I have those people. We can get them out."

Ty not seeing any other option reluctantly agreed.

When they invaded the slavers camp, they were not expecting what they saw. The mud men were powerful sorcerers with earth magic. The Highwaymen took incredible losses. Ty and Expo ran into the cave where they were keeping the slaves. They had to bust into one of the leaders offices to find the keys.

Ty found them and they ran out to release the slaves. Ty and Expo had to fight a few guards and Ty felt the blessing of Tymora because this was dangerous and a little stupid, but it is for all the right reasons. Ty and Expo opened up the gates and started releasing the chains. The slaves started fighting other guards for their freedoms. Ty found Joclyn and released her chain.

Joclyn started to ask "What are you…"

Ty: "No time, let's go."

They ran. They got out of there. The highwaymen and the slaves all ran. If they stayed in the camp the mud men would kill every last one of them. On the road Ty, Expo , and Joclyn and few others were blocked by a wall of earth. They turned to fight and heard a rumbling. Even the earth mages stopped.

Crashing through the wall making Ty, Joclyn , Expo and the others jump out of the way where men riding on great mounts. There was an army with the emblem of a silver moon and a harp. "They got the message." Ty thought. "The harpers are here."

The battle was fought and won by the good, but during the battle Ty saw Expo grab Joclyn . Ty could see Joclyn look back at him and could read her lips, "help me".

Ty jumped to action and got to do something he has been waiting a long time for. He kicked the snot out of Expo . Ty didn't kill him, but did tie him up.

Ty returned with Joclyn to the church in Baldurs Gate. She was hurt pretty bad. She explained to him that " Expo wanted to break into the mud men's camp to steal something magical, but he needed me to activate it."

Ty thinking back to the night, remembers Expo riffling through stuff in the office, but thought he was looking for the keys. Expo probably stole something then.

The next day Ty packed up and started his Journey back home. Joclyn wished him well and promised to try and stay out of trouble.

Practice Profession: Earned 10gp for the 5 days, since Ty was working for an organization. He also picked up 1.8gp in tips and donations. Since this was FBDT money earned must be reduced by lifestyles cost first. So 6.8 will be added to the bank (church funds).

Rites: The random adventure ritual will earn 1d6 days of inspiration when you wake.

Gaining Renown: For helping bring down a camp of slavers Ty earns Renown with The Church of Tymora.

Downtimes 05

Ty sat staring at the paper intently. Jurras and Mycan, high priest of Tymora, stood back waiting.

"Not all people have talent in such things Mr. Bigglesworth. Elf or not, it is something people just..."

"Mycan, please. I have a good feeling about him." Jurras was only barely listening to the priest. He had a hint of a smile and he kept rubbing his ample girth as was his habit. The High priest on the other hand seemed very worried. He didn't like disappointing such a generous donor.

The elf suddenly looked up, "I don't know if I'll remember all the history behind it, but is this what you wanted?" He flicked his hands in a very precise way, saying the prayer as he remembered it and the coin on the table lit up with soft glow. Six sets of eyes widened and Jurras let out a triumphant laugh.

"My child, you can read all the history and theory you want, but when Tymora approves of your action, it will show." Jurras as elated. He knew Tyelknowle would excel in the church. He had skills only priest of Tymora could appreciate and he had a thirst for knowledge and adventure.

Tyelknowle smiled. Mycan nodded his head and lead the young elf to his new novice chamber. He had talent and now he could be taught to use it for good.

Tyelknowle spent his days following the orders of the upper clergy in very simply but religiously significant tasks. He spent his nights reading taking advantage of the fact he only needed four hours of rest.

His favorites were magic theory, history, and languages. He would show he had more talent than even they thought. Books became like family to him. He would have his mouse Burt sit with him, marking his place or bringing him little snacks. He would then try to explain to Burt what he had learned. For months, the biggest complaint anyone made of him was that he would leave others looking for text that Ty had squirreled away.

Storyteller addition:

Ty found a book by chance (is there such a thing in Tymora's temple?) on magical creatures. The entry was from another journal. A legendary fighter from the Harpers, Romos Acco, talked about a time he and a man named Marlos Urnrayle were chasing after an elemental spirit that was called "the mountain that walks". The creature was sort of a legend, no one was really sure if he existed. Marlos Invited Romos to help find this creature. Romos was sort of an expert on this elemental. He told the stories that have been pasted down from Bard to Bard. From mixing everything that is known or told, the creature should not be hard to find.

It is described to be 50 feet tall, with green crystal growths protruding from his body, he is a bipedal monster, and he crushes everything in his path. After years of searching and almost giving up Marlos and Romos found it. Marlos , against Romos wishes, snuck up to the creature while it was sleeping, and casted a spell that tore a chunk off of the creature. He collected it in a portal and the two ran. Marlos and Romos both barely survived.

Once Romos returned with more Harpers to bring down the creature, it was gone and left no trace to track it.

Rewards:

History has improved (10/150) Cost: 6gp. This gold is a cost for helping maintain the temple. Donations earned while traveling and such to the church. (oop: proficiencies cost 1gp a day.)

Downtimes 04

Tyelknowle is recently in Red Larch . He knows these adventurers, maybe one of them can get him a little work. Barikhol lets Ty start working with him. He tells him he is working on making some Brew.

Ty shows up at the location Barikhol gave him and he throws him some gloves and cleaning supplies and says "let's get started." It took a day to clean up some of this old junk, but they finally got it done.

The next day Ty assisted Barikhol in making a keg of ale. Barikhol would send Ty out to get supplies and ask him to check on some things here and there. Honestly Ty really didn't know what he was doing, but Barikhol was pretty good at giving instructions so Tyelknowle could follow them.

One day being out at the market Tyelknowle say a half orc vender:

 “Orc Fingers! Get your Orc Fingers! I got em fresh for ye!” Kids would try and sneak off with some from the cart. Most of the time they were caught by Grund , but a couple times they would succeed. Grund would see them once it is too late and he would shake his fist at them and say “I gonna tell ye mum.” Then he would chuckle. Tyelknowle noticed it was a game with the children. If the children were caught they would pay up, but if they succeeded they won a pickle, err Orc Finger, for free.

It was actually kind of fun watching the kids try. It was most impressive when Tyelknowle saw Josephus and some girl talking to the half orc. Grund was looking right at the girl and she snuck out two pickles right under his nose. Now Grund was kind of a simple creature, but he wasn't blind. She was just good.

When they left Ty saw Josephus and the girl wave back to Grund and show off they won pickles. Grund was surprised, but what Ty found most amazing is that the girl slipped a few coins in Grunds pocket. Ty didn't even notice her do this.

The rest of the week Ty helped with what he could for Barikhol . He also spared a little with the group. There was one match against Rowena where Ty and Bert played a little trick on her. Bert and Ty threw Rowena off by sending Bert crawling up her leg. Rowena found herself on her back with a cute little mouse was staring in her face. "Hey look Bael'Ru, you pinned her."

At the end of the week Barikhol gave Ty his share. It was late. He gave him a bag and said he did well. Barikhol told Ty he would see him tomorrow at breakfast and wished him goodnight.

Practicing a Profession (10): earn 10gp.

Barikhol Downtimes | Home | Character Downtimes | Rowena Downtimes

Game 23 - 26

Detailed Entry

What happened between then and now.

If you’re reading along our adventure. There was a time where life was too overwhelming for me to take good notes. Here is the cliff notes section of what happened.

After the battle at Mirabar, the heroes shared some time with the citizens. They met a druid by the name of Haza who was heading south to a druid ritual.

The ritual turned out to not be what the druids thought. The ritual was going to turn into a sacrifice by the Cult of the Eternal Flame.

The heroes stepped in and fought a very powerful summoned fire elemental.

Armond was tasked to kill Elizar, a fire mage, by his patron, but failed to be the one that ended his life. Grimble was the one that brought down the fire mage.

The moon turned full and Barikhol went through his change. He became a wereboar and the heroes where overwhelmed. They ran and Barikhol rampaged.

(Side story)

Barihol wakes up the next day, naked with other naked people. After quick introductions they are all wereboars cursed by the same man. They have accepted their curse and can control their change at night on a full moon. They haven't gotten to a point where they can change at will.

They take Barikhol back to their camp and he meets the alpha. The only reason Barikhol goes is because there are so many of them and it is kind of intimidating. He is a terrible person and they do terrible things. Something happens and he tells Barikhol to do something terrible. Barikhol’s instincts actually try to compel him to do it, but his monk training kicks in and he resist.

Barikhol fights the Alpha and... long story short, Barikhol is the alpha now.

(/end side story)

The heroes searched for Barikhol for a couple months, but couldn’t find him. One day while in Red Larch they looked up and a floating mountain was hovering near the Feathergale Spires. The heroes went to investigate and found Thurl Merosska dying. It turns out Thurl was a double agent. He was spying on the Cult of the Howling Hatred for Waterdeep. He told the heroes of such and gave them what they needed to get up to the mountain.

The heroes kind of own flying mounts now, and they went to the mountain to attack. This was a dungeon and there were monsters.

But in the throne room is where everything went down. You see one of the rooms the heroes found a fairy named Leaf. Josephus (one of the deceased heroes of Red Larch) was a friend of Leafs. Leaf was very loyal to Josephus, but things happened and he was captured. Leaf never got to tell Josephus the truth.

When the heroes made it to the throne room, they were greeted by Aerisi and Bastian. Aerisi lead the Cult of the Howling Hatred. Bastian was a bit surprised the Heroes of Red Larch made it. Bastian is a cruel man, and his name is feared around the Sword Coast, but not many have seen his face. Rowena knew what he looked like because of Odert inside her head. Armond, knew Bastian for another reason. Bastian was Armonds patron.

Bastian ordered Armond to defend Aerisi with his life and not to allow a scratch to land on her. Armond tried to game the system and Bastian ordered one of his guards to strike her to make Armond fail. When Bastian gave Armond another command Armond resisted. “I will not turn against my friends.”

Bastian said to him, “Then let’s see how you do without me.” Armond felt his power leave him and he attacked. They fought and then off of reflex Armond raised his arm to Eldritch Blast Bastian. A green light flew from his hand and struck Bastian twice knocking him back. “How? This is impossible.”

Leaf said “Armond serves another now. My queen will be his patron, as long as that is ok…” Armond nodded and Bastian ran. Aerisi fell and the Genie that was keeping up the mountain was free. The mountain crashed in the Sumber Hills, in the Dessarin Valley.

The Heroes returned to Red Larch.

Game 27 | Home | Game Notes | Game 27.1

Game 27.1

Detailed Entry

The Devastation Orbs

The heroes wait for 3 days and then take off north. They mount their (flying mounts) and headed towards Triboar. Once they landed and got settled in they were approached by a man on horseback “Ohoy! I am looking for a Barikhol?” A male half-elf from a far is standing at a fruit vendor and looks over at the name Barikhol. He waves and goes about his business. The half-elf looks kind of familiar, but it is hard to place who he is.

After a brief hesitation Barikhol steps up, “I am he. Wut can I do fur ye?” The man on horse back looks at something then hands Barikhol a letter. The letter is from Teria.

“Hello my sweet. We are on our way, please stay put. We can absolutely help with this, but we also need your help. We will explain more once we arrive.”

The heroes took a tour of the town, met some locals, and found shelter for the night. During certain times of the year the town is actually a bit lively during the night. There are bards setup in the streets, multiple taverns to visit, and pretty much any kind of shop one could think of.

Four men in uniform come walking up to the heroes. The symbol on their chest consist of 3 black boars with a red background. The lead officer approaches one of the heroes and keeps his voice low to not cause a scene. The heroes get a sense this is common practice. Their whole time here they haven’t seen too much commotion for a large city. It is probably an appearance thing, the city wants to operate like it is always in control.

“I have been asked to escort you to the presence of Lady Shendrel.” The guards are not hostel and the heroes nod to follow along.

They take everyone through some backroads and into the rear of a business. On entering this place is a back room for what appears to be a winery. There is a large round table and sitting at it is an aged beautiful female that holds herself like an adventurer. She stands up and says “Thank you for coming. I have been wanting to meet with you. I am Lady Shendrel the Lord Protector of Triboar. I am honored to meet the Heroes of Red Larch. Many bards have told your stories and many songs have been sung in your honor.”

Behind her, is the half-elf the heroes saw in the market buying some fruit. “I would like to introduce you to Grevor…” On saying the name, this strikes most of the heroes memories “… you rescued him from the earth cult. Not many made it out alive, but he did. And we are thankful of your rescue.”

Grevor was in the cells across from where the heroes of Red Larch where held.

“Please have a seat.” Once the heroes do servers come out to the table and lay down some wine and some food. Once introductions and niceties have been made, Lady Shendrel says “You are welcomed in this town and you are under my protection while you’re here, but I would be lying if I didn’t say I was concerned by your presence. Usually in the stories when you show up, this means the cults are nearby. Are we in danger?”

The heroes contemplate for a moment before Armond speaks up, “Lady Shendrel, I hope your town isn’t in danger, but there is some cult activity near here and we have come to investigate. I wish to tell you more, but I can’t. We mean you no disrespect, but there is no further information I can give.”

Lady Shendrel pushes “My guards can be of great assistance if they knew what you were looking for we could aid you.”

Armond replies, “If we knew we would share.”

Lady Shendrel sits up in here seat, “Sir Armond, I offered you protection in my city, and offer my aid, there is no reason for you to lie to me.”

Armond tried to recall where his messed up. This was a simple lie, that shouldn’t have raised suspicion. Then he saw that his fairy companion was glowing a different shade of blue. “Well you’re going to be difficult to work with.” Armond muttered to the Leaf.

“You’re right, and I am sorry.” Armond begins, “You see, trust is a difficult thing for my companions and I to freely give. We want to accept you at your word, as it would be really nice, but here is the thing. If the cult could infiltrate Waterdeep, they could do it anywhere.”

Shock. The heroes spoted shock in Lady’s Shendrels eyes. It didn’t touch her face, she is very diplomatic, but it was there. Which is good, the only people that knew of the infiltration in Waterdeep was the Mudbloods and Teria’s and Sesa’s father Lord Bonnet.

At this moment many people came walking into the Winery. There was Tyelknowle, Joclyn, Ander, two water genasi the heroes didn’t know, Sesa, and Teria. “Hello mother.” Teria said “I see you have met my friends.”

“She did kno.” Barikhol said under his breath. “Ye were shocked that we knu.” Barikhol said to Lady Shendrel.

Teria plants a kiss on the top of Barikhol’s head, “Technically, no one knows this, because it never happened.”

Teria and Sesa gave their mother a warm embrace and then Teria says “we need to get to work.”

The mudbloods, Teria and Sesa, Lady Shendrel, and the Heroes of Red Larch start sharing information. The Devastation Orbs in Yartar isn’t the only one. The Mudbloods have been following trails of these weapons for a few tendays. There are many across the sword coast. The cults are losing and they plan on detonating them.

After the loss of the Air Queen, they are desperate. We can no longer stop them alone. So here is the plan…

{Montage of events over the next couple years}

Andar and Barikhol are in waterdeep parkouring from one building to the next. They get over a sun window and watch a group of cultist holding a meeting. The moment they see the dark blue orb, Andar reaches into his pouch and pulls a smoke bomb and lights it. They dive into the room and begin to trade blows.

Armond, Rowena, Thorke (a monk of the Vale of Dancing Waters), and Haza (the dwarven druid the heroes met on the way to the fire cults summoning). They are at the Vale of Dancing Waters. Earth Cult mages taken this place over and ran out the monks. In the cavernous entrance the heroes take their stand. Haza turns into a bear and slams a cult mage into the wall. While another one leaps to attack her from behind, Armond sends a greenish blue light to blast the attacker off her back. Rowena sweeps up a couple mages into her earth hand then blasts them with fire.

Grimble, Grund, Zummy (Grunds sister), Leokas, and Wyer are seen being ambushed on the Stone Bridge by air genasies. The heroes hold their own, Grimble gets blasted off the bridge and gets caught one of the gryphon mounts. This wasn’t an ambush, it was a setup. Flying from the sky are the Feathergale Knights (The real ones) swooping in for a rare on the air cultist.

There is a scene where Barikhol is locked in the Sacred Stone Monastery. Leokas is in there on the outside of the cell. “Just make it through this night, and we can try again.” Bone breaking sounds can be heard from inside the cell as Barikhol shifts.

The Heroes of Red Larch are walking up to Beliard. It has been turned to ash. They walk through the town, but there were no survivors. Tyelknowle buries Victoria (A Lady of Sune). Barikhol buries Eann (the farmer who saw the Cult of Howling Hatred posing as the Feathergale Knights) and his family. The town was devastated with a Fire Orb.

Grimble, Tyelknowle, Teria, Sesa, and many mudbloods are fighting from ship to ship. Shoalar is on board and his ship is losing. Once defeated, he gives up the Orb and distracts the heroes to run away.

A battle field lit by fire and moonlight. Many heroes from the sword coast have come to join in the fight against Bastian and his army. The Sword coast seems to be losing, when out of the woods everyone hears a roar. Not just one roar, but many roars. The heroes of Red Larch all look up to see the moon is full tonight. Then out of the tree cover 10 werecreatures come charging out lead by Barikhol in his wereboar form. They start tearing through the army.

Deep in the caves Armond, Joclyn, Brother Eardon, Otho, and Ander are fighting drow. During the battle Ander fell due to a well-placed arrow. The heroes pressed on but Otho stayed behind with Ander. They find a room and the carvings on the wall are of a map that lead to a place called Fane of the Eye. Marked on the map is a symbol of The Evil Eye.

The next adventure begins with The Protectors of the Coast meeting in the Feathergale Spire. Everyone is looking over this copy of the map, and no one knows where it is from.

Game 23 - 26 | Home | Game Notes | Game 28.0 (Last Two Years)

Game 28.1

Game Day

Game Date: 06/16/18

Detailed Entry

The heroes stand around a map at the Feathergale Spire. They are companied by Feathergale Knights, cartographers, Mud-Bloods, and more. Everyone is having trouble placing their finger on where this map belongs. In the corner written in elvish is the following riddle.

There are four brothers in this world that were all born together:

The first sings a song that is never good,

The second runs and never wearies,

The third drinks and is ever thirsty,

And the fourth eats and is never full.

The heroes of Red Larch, after studying and debating for a bit, Grimble was the first to realize this riddle was naming Air, Water, Earth, Fire. But past that no one knew anything about this map. No one except Rowena.

Upon seeing the map Rowena has a memory about her Grandmother Arlin. Her grandmother was preparing for her last quest. She was accompanied by Rowena’s grandfather and twin brother. Rowena saw them leave and that was the last time. Rowena has moments where she wishes she could have told them bye.

“My sweet Ro, how I wish you never had to find this place.” Arlin said while Rowena was coming out this memory. Rowena turned towards Arlin and immediately tried to give her a hug, but unfortunately Arlin was not there. Rowena tried anyway and Arlin moved her arms in a gesture that would hugging her back.

“How? What… Where are… Are you real?” Rowena went through a few questions before she settled on this one.

With a smile that Rowena remembers, Arlin replied, “I set up this working many years ago. If you ever were to go here I would be able to contact you. I hoped this would never have to happen.”

“What is this place?” Rowena asked.

“We called it, the Fane of the Eye. It is a place between the elemental planes. Traveling through here will take you to the plagued elemental planes. Destroying the cults are the only way to end the Elemental Evil. You and your friends are the closest anyone has ever come to removing this evil from the planes.” Arlin pauses to take another look at Rowena, “Stopping the Elemental Evil will save many planes.”

“What is different now, then when you did this?” Rowena asks, “Why did you fail?”

“Belief”, Arlin replies. “The cults were not known as well back then. They lived in secret, but their belief is strong. Over the last few years you and your friends have pushed them back. You have given them doubt, and this has weakened them.”

“Is she talking to O-Dirt?” Barikhol asks Grimble as everyone in the room is watching Rowena having this conversation with the air.

“OH MY GODS!” Odert said in Rowena’s mind, “The T is silent!” Arlin starts to laugh. “Wut?” Odert continues.

“It is not easy to be a wild mage.” Arlin answers. Then Odert begins to laugh. “I can teach you to open the way as soon as you’re ready.”

“I know what we have to do.” Rowena tells the others.

The next scene Rowena laid out a square pattern and placed each of the 4 elements into the corners. By the time it is finally ready everyone is showing up.

Armond doesn’t have his adventuring gear packed up. The remainder of the Heroes of Red Larch inquire from him what is going on. “Where is your stuff?” Barikhol asked.

“I also know what I must do. You guys go and finish this, but I am needed somewhere else. I have to rescue Josephus.” Armond pauses as everyone looks confused. Josephus died a long time ago. “It turns out anyone killed by the cults their soul goes to the spirit world connected with the elements. Since Josephus was killed by the earth cult, his spirit is wandering around in a part of the spirit world of the Earth Plane. I need to go there and get them released. Freeing them will allow the spirits to travel back to their afterlife.”

The heroes wanted to go with Armond, but knew that now is the time to strike. Armond wanted to go with the rest of the heroes, but knew if they destroy the Elemental Evil the souls would be lost.

“Hurry back, we have a brewery to run.” Barikhol told Armond.

“Same to you.” Armond replied. The shook and Armond watched them open the way into the Planes.

Rowena completed the ritual and the four corners collapsed where it looked like everyone vanished. Armond tilted his head slightly and noticed they collapsed into what looked like a tall sheet of glass. The glass starting shrinking towards the middle like water being sucked down an invisible drain. When the last of the glass disappeared there was heard a loud “pop”.

Somewhere else there could be heard the sound of glass braking and the Heroes of Red Larch were falling, down into a pool of water. The water had a tough current and everyone started swimming, Barikhol was struggling.

Rowena was last to hit the water, and she could see Barikhol was struggling. She tucked into a cannon ball and when she hit the water, the wave pushed Barikhol back up and out of the pull of the current so he could start swimming towards the shore.

This is when two Water Weirds sprang up out of the pool and started attacking the intruders. Barikhol got to shore and threw a mace. “Where the hell did that come from?” Grimble yelled.

“I have no idea!” Barikhol yelled back. Rowena swam past them and released lightning into the water. Everyone’s hair stuck up on their arms, but they could see this started to cook the Water Weirds. Leokas blasted and killed one of them with fire, as Barikhol threw his darts and one sank in the creatures’ eye.

If they were not already, the rest of the heroes crawled out of the water and laid down on the shore. “Let’s take a quick break and dry off before continuing.” Leokas said. The rest of the heroes nodded in agreement.

Game 28.0 (Last Two Years) | Home | Game Notes | Game 30 (with a note about 29)

Game 16

Game Day

Game Date: 05/14/2017

Date in Play: (10) Marpenoth 27, 1491;

TLDR

The Heroes of Red Larch decided to go investigate getting Teria and Sesa’s boat back from the Cult of the Crashing Wave.
Barikhol still dealing with his losing control and channeling his focus almost gets in a fight with Grimble, but goes on a walk before he does. (Sticking with the “Finding Ourselves” Theme)
Tyelknowle found out that Armond invited a necromancer to join them when they go back to the Earth Cults hideout.
Barikhol found a letter from Rowena that she packed up and left. She will return.
The heroes were jumped by the Water Cult the first night in their travels.

Rowena was taken by the Cult of the Crashing Wave.
She learned a few things about the Cult like the names Grimjaw, Reash, and Drosnin
She also learned the name of their god Olhydra.
She also learned that they Cult was taking her for insurance from the Heroes of Red Larch
Rowena freed herself, and ran back to the party.

Detailed Entry

Due to feedback I received I am braking the story up into two stories. One story will have "For Rowena" the other story will have "For Everyone Else". You may choose to read both stories and I am ok with that. I have faith that you can separate story from character knowledge.

For Everyone Else

The adventure started with Tyelknowle returning to Red Larch meeting up with the others over breakfast.

A lot needed to be talked about.

1) The heroes taking this side adventure to retrieve back the boats for Teria and Sesa.

2) Armond agreeing to work with a necromancer to clear out the Earth Cult temple.

3) Why they are going to go after the boat instead of trying to take down the earth cult?

Teria and Sesa joined in on this conversation. At some point Grimble told them, you should continue to Waterdeep to find people to handle this task for you.

Teria replied "That is your answer? Why did we waste time with you all last night then? It would have been much better if you told us this answer before the caravan left!" She stood up kicking the chair over and started to storm out of the Helm at Highsun.

Barikhol jumped up to pause her, "Hold on. Let us work this out. We will help you get back your boat."

Grimble and Tyelknole do not agree with working with a Necromancer. Even to the point of using him. Necromancy is evil as far as society is concerned. Most towns wouldn't need any justification to kill a necromancer.

The argument is that the necromancer could help get what they need from the earth cult, and he is only asking for his knife as payment.

Grimble believes they should be going after the Cult of the Black Earth instead of moving on to the Cult of the Crushing Wave. Tyelknowle seems to agree on this. Armond and Barikhol said they are not ready to return to the Sacred Stone Monastery.

Grimble made some kind of remark that Barikhol screwed up the attack on the Earth Cult last time and Barikhol just about lost it. At last moment Barikhol was able to keep his composure and walked out of the Helm at Highsun.

Barikhol was walking around not really paying attention when he found himself in their room. He saw that all of Rowena's stuff was gone and a note left on the bed.

Friends, I am sorry. I know you needed me for tomorrow, but something is wrong with me and I need answers before it gets worse. I know you will be heading to the water cult location. I will look for you there, but if you go elsewhere send word to Red Larch and I will find you. I am so sorry, I love you guys but I am a liability right now. See you soon, I hope.

This made Barikhol even angrier. He went back into the tavern and slammed the note back on the table.

The discussion end and they heroes made way towards the Water Cult.

(Storyteller Note here: in all the confusion I forgot that the two sisters were traveling along with you. They would have totally joined into this scene. Pretend they did.)

That night during Armond's watch, he took a few steps away because he thought he heard something. He noticed on the ground was running water and it was moving unlike water would.

"Everyone wake up!" Armond screamed. They did and they drew their weapons.

There was a Priest, a Water Genasi, and a handfull of fighters who were there to attack the group.

The Priest went down quickly and the Water Genasi took a couple hard hits and went invisible. After seeing the other drop so quickly the fighters ran.

Armond threw an improbable eldritch blast to hit one before he escaped. They were able to capture and keep one alive.

Tyelknowle and Grimble asked "Everyone ok?" they started healing the group.

Armond asks "How did the water cult know we were out here?"

Everyone looked around and eventually their eyes landed on the sisters.

For Rowena

Rowena steps into her room. Something felt off. Everything in her body told her to run, but she couldn't. Rowena looks down as she feels something cold and wet on her. Its water, but she can't push through it like water.

Rowena trying to figure out what is going on looks around the room. All her stuff is packed up. On the bed is a note. she follows the water. It goes behind her to the corner. It is a large snake like body made purely of water.

Rowena struggles to break free, but she is restrained. She starts to scream, but the water quickly moves over her face and Rowena can't breathe. She realizes she is drowning. It is quiet. Everything is quiet. Her vision starts to blur, and then the room goes dark.

"Why can't we kill her?" one man says

"Brother, I told you. Grimjaw wants her as insurance. These heroes of Red Larch are starting to make a name for themselves." another man that sounds a lot like the first man replied.

Rowena is tied up. She can feel her arms bound in front of her and the rope goes around her neck. Rowena tries a little trick using her prestidigitation to untie the rope but the moment she went to whisper the words and flick the fingers, the magic felt suffocated. Using her Arcana knowledge, she can tell this is some kind of magical rope that mutes casters.

Rowena could tell she could talk just fine, but the moment she would try magic, it stopped. You would think Rowena would be a little frustrated by her situation, but this rope is actually kind of cool.

Her face had a bag over it. She couldn't really see. She could hear voices and movement, but she couldn't make out anything. She knew she was outside. She could feel her Fox nudge her. It was a strange feeling. It was like real, but not at the same time.

"It's ok. We will figure something out." she whispered to the fox.

"Will you now?" a voice replies. "Your frie..." his sentence was cut short by the sound of a man ridding up quickly on horseback. At least Rowena assumed it was a horse.

"The heroes of Red Larch have left." a new voice says. "They are on their way up the Larch Path."

"Let’s go get them." a man says. The group gives words of agreement.

"If we do this, we shall go with our god Olhydra" an older man says, the group says a chant. “To the depths and back.”

It sounded like everyone left. So Rowena maneuvered herself to remove her mask and shake her hair from her face. As soon as her eyes focused she was staring at a rather thick dark blue man.

"Brave." He said, "You see the mask was for your protection. We would have rather you not seen our faces." He pulls out a knife, sharpens it, and then pulls out an apple and starts cutting it. "What is in this for you?"...

((I actually would like to play this out. We can do it between games. But there is some conversation here I am curious where it would go.))

After the talk finishes he tells Rowena, "I won't be too far. I would say don't try anything, but I think you can figure out moving from that spot would not go well."

Rowena actually didn't figure that out. She just now noticed that she wasn't sitting on the ground. She was on some kind of plate.

Once he leaves Rowena felt a familiar feeling bubbling up in her. Her instincts told her to suppress it, but then she saw her fox. Staring straight at her with one of those k9 grins.

The Water Genasi comes running back and so does the others.

"Not now... Must wait for the right moment." Rowena told herself. Suppressing has been difficult and this took some coaxing, but Rowena finally held it down.

"Brother what happen." the Genasi with the apple said.

"Reash. They... They killed Drosnin." he replied. "Take these men and head to the rondeaux. I will bring the girl."

"But you're hurt." Reash said.

"It is a girl. She is suppressed. What she going to do?" he replied.

Reash didn't like it but he followed his brother’s orders.

The brother started doing things to the camp. Rowena watched and realized that he was covering up their trail. The camp was starting to look old, maybe a few weeks.

"It's time to go my half human." the Genasi started to reach down for her and Rowena could hear the yip of a fox.

She let go. She let go of everything that she has been suppressing. She let it out. Wild magic is strongly connected to a mages emotions. Rowena realized that she hadn't been just suppressing her magic, but her emotions as well. She had been trying to stay strong for her spirit, for her friends, for Odert, and she was realizing just now, for herself.

Rowena let it all out yelling, screaming, crying, laughing... with these emotions came the wild magic. The world slowed down. Rowena could see she was moving twice as fast as before. She could feel her skin soften like it was as weak as paper.

The Water Genasi felt the same. "What is this? How is this happening?" He started looking around because he could also hear music playing nearby. The Genasi looks over at Rowena and down at her bonds. "You can't be doing this."

"But I think I am." she replied. A long beard of feathers grew on her face. "Just once I would like to say a line and my magic make me look bad ass. Is that really too much to ask?" She looks over at her fox and watches his head tilt. Then Rowena braced for being hit with iron skillet. When she opened her eyes Rowena wasn't tied up anymore. She was standing 60 feet away looking back watching the plate trap go off in the genasi's face. Electric eels came flying out biting and shocking the genasi. He didn't stand a chance.

Rowena went running back in the direction from where the others came. She knew the hills, she would just need to get her bearings.

"mi lass, look up." Odert said "I can help wid dis one."

Rowena did as he said and she felt her arm raise up and point. "Dis way."

She started running again.

Rowena heard the voices she wasn't sure what they were talking about, but she knew who they were.

Child Topics

(G16) Riverguard Keep

Game 18 | Home | Game Notes | Game 22